<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?> 

<adat>

	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>April</honap>
		<nap>25</nap>
		<cim>Fidesz wins election with two-thirds majority</cim>
		<szoveg>Conservative opposition party Fidesz with 53 percent of the popular vote, giving the party a two-thirds majority in Parliament. The far-right Jobbik party enters the Hungarian parliament for the first time, winning 47 seats.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2010_apr_25.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>party Fidesz</elotte>
		<szavak>wins national elections</szavak>
		<linkek>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hungarian_parliamentary_election,_2010#Combined_results</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>June</honap>
		<nap>11</nap>
		<cim>Government MPs propose far-reaching media law reforms</cim>
		<szoveg>Fidesz MPs Antal Rogán and András Cser-Palkovics (HU), &quot;On the Freedom of the Press and the Fundamental Rules on Media Contents,&quot; to the parliamentary Committee on Culture and the Press. Controversial elements include a new &quot;media constitution,&quot; outlining content regulation for all media; new registration requirements for media outlets, including print and online media; the creation of a powerful media regulatory board; and a new public broadcasting structure.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/11_06_2010.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Palkovics</elotte>
		<szavak>present a new media bill</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.parlament.hu/irom39/00363/00363.pdf</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>June</honap>
		<nap>14</nap>
		<cim>Opposition submits 44 amendments</cim>
		<szoveg>Hungarian opposition parties, the proposed media legislation, submit 44  amendments to the bill in Parliament. Only one of these amendments, which was submitted by the nationalist Jobbik party, is passed.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>opposition parties,</elotte>
		<szavak>strongly criticizing</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.politics.hu/20100616/opposition-parties-strongly-criticize-media-bill-in-heated-debate/</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>June</honap>
		<nap>21</nap>
		<cim>Parliament votes on amendments to media law</cim>
		<szoveg>Just ten days after it was first proposed, parliament a range of amendments to the media law package. The vote on new content regulations and the so-called media &quot;constitution&quot; is postponed until the fall session, in response to criticism from opposition parties, unions and civil organizations which claim the package is being fast-tracked through Parliament without public debate.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Parliament</elotte>
		<szavak>votes on</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.politics.hu/20100622/parliament-votes-on-amendments-to-media-law-package</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>June</honap>
		<nap>23</nap>
		<cim>International journalist organizations condemn media law package</cim>
		<szoveg>The European Federation of Journalists (EFJ) the new media legislation, saying it &quot;does not meet European standards of diversity and plurality and turns the clock back to a time when Hungary lived under . the shadow of state control of media.&quot; A day later, the International Press Institute (IPI) Fidesz for using its two-thirds parliamentary majority to &quot;rush through a media package that would grant the government strong influence over key media outlets.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2010_jun_23.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>(EFJ);(IPI)</elotte>
		<szavak>condemns;criticizes</szavak>
		<linkek>http://europe.ifj.org/en/articles/european-journalists-reject-the-new-hungarian-media-bill-andcall-for-new-talks;http://www.freemedia.at/singleview/5011/</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>June</honap>
		<nap>23</nap>
		<cim>Media professionals criticize draft media law package</cim>
		<szoveg>Media professionals and journalist groups tell the parliamentary culture and media committee that on the bill is needed. Laszlo Czegledi, chairman of the Hungarian Television Supervisory Board, argues that the package merits more than just one debate in a committee hearing. Eva Simon, media lawyer with the Hungarian Civil Liberties Union (TASZ), warns that the new rules for online media would be &quot;impractical and impossible to implement.&quot; The groups also raise questions about the proposed Media Council. Its members are to be appointed for nine-year terms, and its director appointed by the prime minister.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://i.imgur.com/k1shA.gif</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>committee that</elotte>
		<szavak>more discussion</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.politics.hu/20100625/professionals-unions-put-views-on-media-law-to-parliamentary-committee/</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>June</honap>
		<nap>24</nap>
		<cim>OSCE demands &quot;halt&quot; to new media reforms</cim>
		<szoveg>Dunja Mijatovic, the OSCE Representative on Freedom of the Media, the Hungarian Government to stop drafting media legislation that is to be voted on next week, and start public consultations involving professional stakeholders to modify the draft laws. &quot;The proposed laws are highly worrisome regarding media freedom in your country,&quot; the Representative writes Foreign Minister Janos Martonyi. &quot;Their adoption could lead to all broadcasting being subordinated to political decisions.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2011_jan_18.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>the Media,</elotte>
		<szavak>calls on</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.osce.org/fom/69491</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>June</honap>
		<nap>29</nap>
		<cim>Media law package vote delayed, constitutional amendment passed</cim>
		<szoveg>The vote on most parts of the media law package  say the Fidesz MPs sponsoring the bills, but meanwhile Parliament amends Article 61 of Hungary&#39;s constitution on freedom of speech and freedom of opinion to pave the way for the new legislation. The constitutional amendment also defines the task of public service media, which is to include a role in &quot;preserving the national and European identity, preserving and enriching Hungarian and minority languages, strengthening national cohesion and fulfilling the needs of national, ethnic, religious communities and of the family.&quot; The votes on the controversial parts of the legislative package that relate to the new, powerful media supervisory authority and a code laying out new content regulations are delayed to July and October, respectively.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>law package</elotte>
		<szavak>will be delayed,</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.politics.hu/20100629/fidesz-delays-vote-on-controversial-media-bills</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>July</honap>
		<nap>8</nap>
		<cim>President signs constitutional amendment</cim>
		<szoveg>signs (HU) which facilitates the new media law package (see 29 June).</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/08_07_2010.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>;signs</elotte>
		<szavak>President Sólyom;the constitutional amendment</szavak>
		<linkek>http://tinyurl.com/65fdfed;http://www.kozlonyok.hu/nkonline/MKPDF/hiteles/mk10129.pdf</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>July</honap>
		<nap>19</nap>
		<cim>Washington Post editorial slams new media legislation</cim>
		<szoveg>The Washington Post publishes criticizing Hungary&#39;s new media legislation, calling it, &quot;a phenomenon not seen in Central Europe since the collapse of Communist rule.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2010_jul_19.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>publishes</elotte>
		<szavak>an editorial</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2010/07/18/AR2010071802529.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>July</honap>
		<nap>22</nap>
		<cim>Parliament passes overhaul of media regulation structure</cim>
		<szoveg>Parliament passes Law 82/210, of the proposed new media law package, which overhauls the country&#39;s media regulation structure and establishes a new, centralized media supervisory authority. Under the new law, the National Telecommunications Authority (NHH) and the Radio and Television Authority (ORTT) will be merged into a new National Media and Telecommunications Authority (NMHH). The head of NMHH, appointed by the prime minister for renewable 9-year terms, will become the automatic nominee for the chairpersonship of the Media Council, a new five-member board nominated by a Parliamentary committee, with members also to serve indefinitely renewable 9-year terms.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2010_jul_22.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>82/210,</elotte>
		<szavak>a major piece</szavak>
		<linkek>http://merlin.obs.coe.int/iris/2010/8/article34.en.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>July</honap>
		<nap>28</nap>
		<cim>Civil liberties group claims media laws unconstitutional</cim>
		<szoveg>The Hungarian Civil Liberties Union (TASZ) of the media law package, arguing it fails to meet established European freedom of press standards and contains bills with several unconstitutional clauses that would have a chilling effect on free speech. The statement also denounces the government&#39;s fast-track legislative process that is taking place &quot;without any previous consultation, open debate with stakeholders, experts or journalists.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://i.imgur.com/k1shA.gif</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>(TASZ)</elotte>
		<szavak>releases a critique</szavak>
		<linkek>http://tasz.hu/en/freedom-speech/hclu-protests-against-proposed-new-media-legislation</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>August</honap>
		<nap>10</nap>
		<cim>New media regulatory structure becomes law</cim>
		<szoveg>(HU) comes into effect (see 22 July).</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2010_aug_10.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>;</elotte>
		<szavak>Law 82/2010</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.kozlonyok.hu/nkonline/MKPDF/hiteles/mk10129.pdf</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>August</honap>
		<nap>11</nap>
		<cim>Annamária Szalai appointed head of NMHH</cim>
		<szoveg>Prime Minister Viktor Orbán to head the new, converged media and telecommunications regulatory authority, the NMHH, for a nine-year term. Szalai, a former Fidesz MP, also becomes the automatic nominee to head the Media Council.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2010_aug_11.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Viktor Orbán</elotte>
		<szavak>appoints Annamária Szalai</szavak>
		<linkek>http://bbj.hu/politics/new-media-authority-head-promises-fast-firm-restructuring_53889</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>September</honap>
		<nap>6</nap>
		<cim>European Commission: &quot;no reason to intervene&quot;</cim>
		<szoveg>&quot;The European Commission is fully dedicated to protecting basic freedoms,&quot; says European Commissioner for Digital Agenda Neelie Kroes, but currently in the Hungarian situation. Kroes&#39; statement comes in response to recent debate in the European Parliament over new legislation in Hungary, Estonia and Romania that some MEPs say restricts freedom of information and increases government control over the media.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=50HyJ12cMME</video>
		<elotte>but currently</elotte>
		<szavak>&quot;sees no reason to intervene&quot;</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.politics.hu/20100908/brussels-decides-against-intervening-on-hungarys-media-law</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>September</honap>
		<nap>15</nap>
		<cim>OSCE says media package puts &quot;chilling effect&quot; on press</cim>
		<szoveg>OSCE Representative on Freedom of the Media Hungarian Minister of Foreign Affairs Janos Martonyi to reconsider the media law package, warning that it would &quot;seriously restrict media freedom, curb the independence of the press, abolish the autonomy of public service media and impose a chilling effect on freedom of expression.&quot; She releases an expert legal review of the media law package by Karol Jakubowicz, and urges Hungary to &quot;take into consideration the detailed recommendations of the analysis when rewriting the legislation.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2010_szept_15.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>the Media</elotte>
		<szavak>Dunja Mijatovic urges</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.osce.org/fom/72229</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>September</honap>
		<nap>21</nap>
		<cim>OSCE media rep: Hungary&#39;s media laws &quot;totalitarian&quot;</cim>
		<szoveg>Attending a Budapest conference, OSCE Representative on Freedom of the Media Dunja Mijatovic laws like Hungary&#39;s new media law package &quot;have only been known in totalitarian regimes where governments are restricting free speech.&quot; Mijatovic says the laws are not in compliance with the OSCE standards Hungary has agreed to uphold.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2011_jan_18.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Dunja Mijatovic</elotte>
		<szavak>claims that</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.france24.com/en/20100921-hungarian-media-law-like-totalitarian-regime-osce?quicktabs_1=1</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>October</honap>
		<nap>12</nap>
		<cim>New Media Council sworn in</cim>
		<szoveg>A parliamentary committee appoints the members of the new Media Council. Candidates nominated by the ruling Fidesz party are appointed to all four positions: János Auer, Tamás Kollárik, András Koltay, and Ágnes Vass. András Cser-Palkovics, the committee&#39;s chairman, says the decision was based strictly on professional competence, but blogger Eva Balogh that &quot;László Majtényi, the former chairman of the earlier board supervising the media, said that out of the four people he had heard of one, András Koltay.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Eva Balogh</elotte>
		<szavak>notes critically</szavak>
		<linkek>http://esbalogh.typepad.com/hungarianspectrum/2010/10/the-new-hungarian-media-council.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>November</honap>
		<nap>2</nap>
		<cim>&quot;Media Constitution&quot; adopted</cim>
		<szoveg>Parliament adopts Law 104/2010, the so-called which introduces content regulations on all media, including broadcast, print and online audiovisual media, as well as media content from other countries deemed to be aimed at Hungarian audiences. Among many controversial elements, the law includes new rules on source protection and requirements for media outlets to provide &quot;balanced&quot; coverage.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2010_nov_02.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>so-called</elotte>
		<szavak>&quot;Media Constitution,&quot;</szavak>
		<linkek>http://tinyurl.com/5tvfaz5</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>November</honap>
		<nap>9</nap>
		<cim>Media, rights groups criticize media constitution</cim>
		<szoveg>The International Press Institute (IPI) and the Hungarian Civil Liberties Union (HCLU) condemn the newly adopted &quot;media constitution.&quot; HCLU&#39;s that the law imposes new obligations on media that will considerably restrict press freedom. IPI Press Freedom Manager the law&#39;s weakened provisions on source protection for journalists, and IPI board member Ivan Lipovecz claims the law will make public broadcasting dependent on the government.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>HCLU&#39;s;Manager</elotte>
		<szavak>Eva Simon argues;Anthony Mills criticizes</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.politics.hu/20101104/human-rights-group-appeals-to-top-court-over-media-constitution;http://www.freemedia.at/singleview/5213/</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>November</honap>
		<nap>9</nap>
		<cim>&quot;Media constitution&quot; becomes law</cim>
		<szoveg>The &quot;Media Constitution,&quot; ,comes into effect. This law would later be amended, in March 2011, to address objections by the European Commission.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Constitution,&quot;</elotte>
		<szavak>Law 104/2010</szavak>
		<linkek>http://cmcs.ceu.hu/files/act_civ_media_content.pdf</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>December</honap>
		<nap>2</nap>
		<cim>Papers protest with blank front pages</cim>
		<szoveg>Several Hungarian publications – the daily Népszava newspaper and the weeklies Magyar Narancs and Élet és Irodalom – in protest of the new media laws. &quot;The bill would provide total supervision of electronic, Internet and print media to the Media Council and through them to the government&quot; &quot;With that, press freedom would come to an end in Hungary as of Jan. 1, 2011.&quot; The editor-in-chief of Élet és Irodalom claims the bill is clearly aimed &quot;against journalists, against transparency,&quot; and that &quot;from now on the press will be under constant pressure.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/02_12_2010.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Irodalom –;government&quot;</elotte>
		<szavak>run blank front pages;Magyar Narancs reports.</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-11899075;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2010-12-02/hungarian-weeklies-protest-proposed-media-law-with-blank-covers.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>December</honap>
		<nap>13</nap>
		<cim>International organizations condemn new media bill</cim>
		<szoveg>Freedom House and the European Newspaper Publishers&#39; Association (ENPA) release statements expressing concern at the latest draft media law. &quot;This legislation, combined with other troubling moves against the media, will be a major setback for press freedom in Hungary,&quot; Managing Editor of Freedom House&#39;s annual Freedom of the Press index. &quot;Of particular concern is the wording of the supposed &#39;violations&#39; which is very is broad, creating an environment conducive to significant misuse, especially given the extremely polarized political environment in the country.&quot; The ENPA the &quot;extensive fines against journalists and publishers if they refuse to disclose their sources or publish information deemed inappropriate by the government&quot; which the new bill imposes, and claims that &quot;the proposed law, if passed, would seriously endanger freedom of the press by creating room for a subjective judgment about any individual news story and penalise publishers and editors through government-controlled regulatory bodies.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2010_dec_13.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>freedom in Hungary,&quot;;The ENPA</elotte>
		<szavak>said Karin Karlekar;warns against</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.freedomhouse.org/template.cfm?page=70&amp;release=1292;http://www.wan-press.org/article18748.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>December</honap>
		<nap>20</nap>
		<cim>Hundreds attend protest organized by Facebook</cim>
		<szoveg>Up to 1,500 protestors for press freedom, organized by local students (HU).</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>Tüntetés a médiatörvény ellen</foto_alairas>
		<video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0XRxHctRaBQ</video>
		<elotte>protestors;students</elotte>
		<szavak>attend a demonstration;through Facebook</szavak>
		<linkek>http://tinyurl.com/6jud3qg;http://www.facebook.com/event.php?eid=116460895085881</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>December</honap>
		<nap>20</nap>
		<cim>Hungarian government claims similar laws are found in other European states</cim>
		<szoveg>The Ministry of Public Administration and Justice publishes to international criticisms of the media law package, citing equivalent legislation in other EU-member countries.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>publishes</elotte>
		<szavak>a detailed response</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.kormany.hu/en/ministry-of-public-administration-and-justice/news/criticisms-and-answers-formulated-on-the-subject-of-the-proposed-media-act-examined-in-a-european-context</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>December</honap>
		<nap>21</nap>
		<cim>Parliament passes Media Act, final part of Hungarian media law package</cim>
		<szoveg>Parliament, the final and most controversial piece of the media law package. The law grants the Media Council powers to fine, suspend and shut down print, electronic and online media for breaches to stipulations in the new media laws that include a number of controversial new content regulations. The law specifies sanctions for content that does not provide &quot;balanced coverage,&quot; infringes upon human dignity, offends public morality, or fails to report on events of public interest. The Media Council will be authorized to levy fines that may reach $950,000 for television stations and $119,000 for newspapers and online news portals. The law also establishes a new body that will manage public service media under a new centralized production system. Members of Parliament of the oppositional LMP party pasted tape over their mouths in protest during the vote, while two of its members held up a sign saying: &quot;Hungarian freedom of the press—it lived for 21 years.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>Parliament passes Media Act, final part</foto_alairas>
		<video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DZnoppMqqTE</video>
		<elotte>Parliament</elotte>
		<szavak>passes the Media Act</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.boston.com/news/world/europe/articles/2010/12/21/hungary_passes_contentious_new_media_law/</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>December</honap>
		<nap>21</nap>
		<cim>DJ suspended for on-air protest</cim>
		<szoveg>The host of the popular radio program &quot;180 minutes,&quot; Attila Mong, and his producer Zsolt Bogar for holding a minute of silence in protest of the new media laws during their morning radio program.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WCCOBUvCAi0</video>
		<elotte>Zsolt Bogar</elotte>
		<szavak>are suspended</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.npr.org/2011/01/15/132964317/Critics-Fear-Democracy-Is-Eroding-In-Hungary</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>December</honap>
		<nap>22</nap>
		<cim>EP groups publish statements against law</cim>
		<szoveg>The Liberal (ALDE) and Green/EFA Groups in European Parliament publish statements condemning the media law. ALDE leader &quot;the time of Pravda is over. This new law is unacceptable.&quot; Greens/EFA co-president &quot;This draconian media law is an echo of Europe&#39;s undemocratic past&quot;.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2010_dec_22-V3.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>ALDE leader;co-president</elotte>
		<szavak>Guy Verhofstadt says:;Rebecca Harms says:</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.alde.eu/alde-group/guy-verhofstadt-mep-leader-alde-group/;http://www.greens-efa.eu/hungary-media-law-2989.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>December</honap>
		<nap>22</nap>
		<cim>OSCE condemns new media law, says it &quot;endangers media freedom&quot;</cim>
		<szoveg>The OSCE Representative on Freedom of the Media, Dunja Mijatovic, issues her saying that the new media law &quot;violates OSCE media freedom standards and endangers editorial independence and media pluralism.&quot; She takes particular aim at the &quot;unusually broad powers&quot; given to the new media authority and media council, &quot;led exclusively by members supported by the governing party,&quot; which constitute a &quot;concentration of power in regulatory authorities [that] is unprecedented in European democracies&quot;; the &quot;absence of clearly defined guidelines,&quot; which makes it &quot;impossible for journalists to know when they are in breach of the law&quot;; and the way the law &quot;endangers the political independence of public service media,&quot; since the governing party had nominated all new heads of the public service media, and the media authority now controls their budgets.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/08_03_2011.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>issues her</elotte>
		<szavak>strongest statement to date,</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.osce.org/fom/74687</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>December</honap>
		<nap>22</nap>
		<cim>International press condemns new media law</cim>
		<szoveg>The new Hungarian media law receives in the European press. The Spanish newspaper El País claims the media law &quot;practically finishes off the freedom of the press.&quot; The German conservative daily Die Welt goes further and headlines its report &quot;Führerstaat Ungarn,&quot; making a direct comparison to the 1930s, and warns that &quot;we can see how quickly a democracy can destroy itself.&quot; Romania Libera compares the legislation to the Hungarian government &quot;stepping with a heavy boot on the neck of the Hungarian media.&quot; Italy&#39;s Corriere della Sera calls the bill a &quot;muzzle law.&quot; The Polish Gazeta Wyborcza publishes  with the Hungarian media on its front page, &quot;which Prime Minister Orbán wants to silence.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2010_dec_22-V2.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>law receives;Wyborcza publishes</elotte>
		<szavak>a hostile reception;a solidarity message</szavak>
		<linkek>http://esbalogh.typepad.com/hungarianspectrum/2010/12/quite-a-day-serious-warnings-for-hungary.html;http://wyborcza.pl/1715307,0.html?skan=8854471</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>December</honap>
		<nap>23</nap>
		<cim>Foreign governments express concern, criticism of new media law</cim>
		<szoveg>International politicians respond to the Media Act with The Foreign Minister of Luxembourg, Jean Asselborn, questions Hungary&#39;s right to assume the EU&#39;s rotating six-month presidency on January 1. The law &quot;raises the question of whether such a country is worthy of leading the EU,&quot; Asselborn says, adding that &quot;until now Lukashenka was considered to be the last dictator in Europe.&quot; On December 22, a spokesperson for German Chancellor Angela Merkel calls on Hungary to &quot;take into account&quot; the criticisms which the OSCE has formulated of the new Hungarian media laws and to &quot;verify that the law respects fundamental EU freedoms.&quot; German Foreign Minister Guido Westerwelle interrupts his holiday to call his Hungarian counterpart in order to discuss the &quot;possibilities of changes in the media laws.&quot; On the 23rd, German Deputy Foreign Minister Werner the new law is &quot;reason for serious concern,&quot; and Czech Foreign Minister Karel that the way the law is drafted &quot;is really dangerous.&quot; On December 30, Hoyer says in an interview: &quot;I assume that the final word by the Hungarian government hasn&#39;t been spoken yet on this issue [..]. It would be very good if this issue could be cleared up quickly.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/asselborn_jean.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>Jean Asselborn</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>respond to the Media Act with;Werner;Karel</elotte>
		<szavak>increasing criticism.;Hoyer says;Schwarzenberg says</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.offnews.info/verArticulo.php?contenidoID=27108;http://www.reuters.com/article/2010/12/30/idUSLDE6BT0D620101230;http://praguemonitor.com/2010/12/27/czech-foreign-minister-criticises-hungarian-media-law</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>December</honap>
		<nap>23</nap>
		<cim>International groups say new media laws violate free press standards</cim>
		<szoveg>, the European Federation of Journalists the International Press Institute and the European Alliance of News Agencies  all issue statements condemning Hungary&#39;s new media legislation.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2010_dec_23-V1.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>;Journalists;Institute;Agencies</elotte>
		<szavak>Amnesty International;(EFJ);(IPI);(EANA)</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.amnesty.org/en/news-and-updates/sweeping-new-media-law-threatens-freedom-expression-hungary-2010-12-23;http://europe.ifj.org/en/articles/journalists-question-hungarys-leadership-of-europe-as-media-law-provokes-outrage;http://www.freemedia.at/singleview/5248/;http://www.newsalliance.org/news.htm</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>December</honap>
		<nap>23</nap>
		<cim>PM Orbán on changing laws: &quot;we don&#39;t even dream of such a thing&quot;</cim>
		<szoveg>On December 23, Janos Lazar, the head of Fidesz&#39;s parliamentary group, if the new media law is applied &quot;in a wrong way, or there are problems,&quot; parliament would change it. But in an interview on the conservative Hungarian TV station HírTV, his commitment to the legislation, citing similar laws in other European countries, and vowing that his government has no intentions of changing the laws: &quot;we don&#39;t even dream of such a thing.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2010_dec_23-V2.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>parliamentary group,;HírTV,</elotte>
		<szavak>promises that;Prime Minister Orbán reiterates</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-12070204;http://esbalogh.typepad.com/hungarianspectrum/2010/12/viktor-orb%C3%A1ns-views-on-the-media-law.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>December</honap>
		<nap>24</nap>
		<cim>European Commissioner Kroes writes Hungarian government</cim>
		<szoveg>European Commissioner Kroes writes a about the latest new Hungarian media law to Tibor Navracsics, the Hungarian Minister of Public Administration and Justice. Kroes references concerns about the law that have been &quot;expressed by numerous commentators&quot;, including the &quot;very broad competences&quot; assigned to the new media regulatory authority and its doubtful capacity to act independently, and the applicability of some of the law&#39;s provisions to broadcasters established in other EU Member States, &quot;which raises potential questions of coherence with one of the basic principles of the Audiovisual Media Services Directive.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/52/Neelie_Kroes_2010-09-14.jpg/634px-Neelie_Kroes_2010-09-14.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>writes a</elotte>
		<szavak>first letter</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.kormany.hu./download/8/01/10000/kroes.pdf</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>December</honap>
		<nap>26</nap>
		<cim>Washington Post: the &#39;Putinization of Hungary&#39;</cim>
		<szoveg>The headline of a critical raises the spectre of the &#39;Putinization of Hungary&#39;. The editors decry Orbán&#39;s &quot;populist and power-hungry government&quot; which &quot;has just adopted a media law more suited to an authoritarian regime than to a Western democracy.&quot; The government, they warn, has &quot;proceeded to take over or attack the authority of every institution it did not control, including the presidency, the Supreme Court and the state audit office,&quot; while &quot;the central bank is now under its assault.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2010_dec_26.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>critical</elotte>
		<szavak>Washington Post editorial</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2010/12/26/AR2010122601791.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>December</honap>
		<nap>30</nap>
		<cim>Hungarian government responds to European Commissioner Kroes</cim>
		<szoveg>Deputy Prime Minister to European Commissioner Kroes&#39; letter, claiming that no part of the legislation &quot;contains provisions which are not found in the legislation of one or more EU member states&quot; and asserting the government&#39;s confidence that &quot;every aspect of the legislation will withstand the severest scrutiny.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Prime Minister</elotte>
		<szavak>Tibor Navracsics responds</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.europarl.europa.eu/meetdocs/2009_2014/documents/libe/dv/navracsics_kroes_humedialaw_291210/navracsics_kroes_humedialaw_291210en.pdf</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2010</ev>
		<honap>December</honap>
		<nap>31</nap>
		<cim>Media Act becomes law</cim>
		<szoveg>The Media Act, is published in the Hungarian Official Journal, and enters into force on January 1, the first day of Hungary&#39;s Presidency of the EU. The law would later be amended, in March 2011, to address objections by the European Commission.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wc40sfwhb8s</video>
		<elotte>The Media Act,</elotte>
		<szavak>Law 185/2010,</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.mediatanacs.hu/uploads/9/11/1296064942act_clxxxv_2010_hungarian_media.pdf</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>3</nap>
		<cim>&quot;Freedom of the press in Hungary comes to an end&quot;</cim>
		<szoveg>Two Hungarian newspapers, Népszabadság and Népszava, to the media law. Népszabadság runs the sentence &quot;Freedom of the press in Hungary comes to an end&quot; on the front page, in all 27 official EU languages. The German newspaper taz reprints the front page in solidarity.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2011_jan_03.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Népszava,</elotte>
		<szavak>publish front-page protests</szavak>
		<linkek>http://apple.copydesk.org/2011/01/03/a-page-one-press-freedom-protest-today-in-budapest-hungary/</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>4</nap>
		<cim>Government releases incomplete translation of media laws</cim>
		<szoveg>The Hungarian government sends foreign embassies and the European Commission a translation of the Media Act, but news portal on January 6 that the translation is missing several key paragraphs. A complete translation is provided on January 10.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/04_01_2011-V2.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>news portal</elotte>
		<szavak>Origo.hu reveals</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.euractiv.com/en/future-eu/barroso-media-freedom-our-sacred-principle-news-501012</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>4</nap>
		<cim>New York Times editorial: &quot;Mr Orbán Forgets&quot;</cim>
		<szoveg>The New York Times criticizing the media law, saying it &quot;marks a sorry step back toward the kind of political censorship Hungary suffered under Communist rule.&quot; According to the paper, the laws &quot;should have no place in a democratic Europe ... Mr. Orbán may have forgotten, but Hungary&#39;s tragic history has taught its people that a free press - and a checked government - cannot be taken for granted.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/04_01_2011.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Times</elotte>
		<szavak>publishes an editorial</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.nytimes.com/2011/01/04/opinion/04tue2.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>4</nap>
		<cim>French government assails media law, Germany suggests limiting Hungarian EU Presidency</cim>
		<szoveg>French government spokesman the Hungarian media law is &quot;incompatible with the application of ideas on press freedom that have been validated in European treaties&quot;, and adds that all EU member states need to take a strong diplomatic position to persuade Hungary to put the law &quot;between parentheses.&quot; On January 5, German Deputy Foreign Minister Hungary is now no longer in a position to lead negotiations over media issues with neighboring countries such as Belarus and Ukraine during its EU presidency. On January 6, the leader of the Socialists and Democrats group in the European Parliament, Martin Schulz, requests the parliament&#39;s committee on civil liberties to investigate the new law, so Parliament &quot;can decide whether or not to open procedures laid down in article seven of the Lisbon Treaty.&quot; (Article seven lays out procedures to defend EU treaty values, which could lead to suspension of a member state&#39;s right to vote on EU decisions.) &quot;We cannot allow Hungary or any other government to drive a coach and horses through the fundamental values of the European Union,&quot; Schulz says in .</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yShAUWzcA9s</video>
		<elotte>spokesman;German Deputy Foreign Minister;Schulz says in</elotte>
		<szavak>Francois Baroin says;Werner Hoyer suggests;a statement</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.euractiv.com/en/future-eu/france-blasts-hungarian-media-law-news-500976;http://www.politics.hu/20110105/germany-in-unprecedented-move-to-limit-hungarys-eu-presidency/;http://www.socialistsanddemocrats.eu/gpes/public/detail.htm?id=135072&amp;section=NER&amp;category=NEWS&amp;request_locale=EN</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>5</nap>
		<cim>Internet &quot;blackout&quot; protest for Hungary</cim>
		<szoveg>Blogs and websites such as popular BitTorrent site The Pirate Bay take part in a</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AouTV3TPB28</video>
		<elotte>part in a</elotte>
		<szavak>&quot;Blackout for Hungary.&quot;</szavak>
		<linkek>http://news.netcraft.com/archives/2011/01/05/blackout-protests-against-hungary-media-law.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>5</nap>
		<cim>Turkish newspaper calls for Hungary to be stripped of EU Presidency</cim>
		<szoveg>The Turkish newspaper Hurriyet republishes the Népszabadság front page headline of January 3, protesting the new Media Act, and in an editorial calls the law &quot;a transparent outrage.&quot; Hungary should be stripped of its turn to hold the EU&#39;s rotating presidency, as &quot;no other sanction fits the crime that Hungary&#39;s government has committed against its own citizenry, against democracy and against the essential values of Europe in the 21st Century.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/05_01_2011.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>rotating presidency,</elotte>
		<szavak>Hurriyet argues,</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.hurriyetdailynews.com/n.php?n=strip-hungary-of-eu-presidency-2011-01-05</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>6</nap>
		<cim>Orbán hits back at European critics</cim>
		<szoveg>Prime Minister Orbán tells journalists that the &quot;interference&quot; by Germany and France was &quot;an insult&quot; and &quot;too hasty and unnecessary,&quot; and demands that the French government &quot;return to the level of reality.&quot; It is &quot;not up to the French or the Germans&quot; to say whether the Hungarian law complies with EU standards, &quot;Not one single state, France included, has the right to criticise and ask Hungary to do something.&quot; Orbán declares: &quot;I defy anyone to find anything in our law that is not in other EU member states&#39; media laws.&quot; Nevertheless he says that Hungary will &quot;accept any procedure that the EU starts.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>EU standards,</elotte>
		<szavak>he adds:</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2011/jan/06/hungary-hits-out-france-germany-eu</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>6</nap>
		<cim>EC President demands &quot;clarification&quot;</cim>
		<szoveg>The President of the European Commission, José Manuel Barroso, announces that he will discuss the new media legislation with Prime Minister Orbán when he meets him in Budapest tomorrow. &quot;The Commissioner responsible in a letter to the Hungarian authorities has expressed some concerns and what of course I would like to have from the Hungarian authorities is a clarification of the situation and, if possible, let&#39;s say lifting of the doubts that exist,&quot; noting that media freedom is &quot;sacred&quot; in the EU.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Iv8FKfM7a7Y</video>
		<elotte>exist,&quot;</elotte>
		<szavak>Barroso says,</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.irishtimes.com/newspaper/world/2011/0106/1224286871106.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>6</nap>
		<cim>Journalist organizations call for European action against Hungary</cim>
		<szoveg>The European Federation of Journalists (EFJ) European Commission President Barroso to analyze Hungary&#39;s new media law, which the EFJ considers a breach of European law, and its implementation. The EFJ stresses that the EU should not just examine technical criteria that are covered by the Audiovisual Services Directive, but also how the law fits with the Fundamental Rights Charter. &quot;We are convinced that it will be necessary to launch an infringement procedure against Hungary under Article 6 of the EU treaty,&quot; the EFJ . On January 7, Human Rights Watch that the EU &quot;should press Hungary&quot; to address its &quot;serious human rights shortcomings, beginning with a problematic media law.&quot; On January 10, the Committee to Protect Journalists (CPJ) Prime Minister Orbán, calling on him &quot;to work toward the immediate repeal of Hungary&#39;s new, severely restrictive media law.&quot; Outlining its issues with the new Media Act, the CPJ concludes that &quot;nearly all of the measure&#39;s 229 pages are devoted to restrictions on free expression and politicized means of enforcing those limits.&quot; Reporters Without Borders (RSF), meanwhile, had already released a on New Year&#39;s Eve, urging the European Parliament &quot;to make discussion of [the new media] law an emergency item&quot; and to adopt a resolution condemning the law, which it called &quot;incompatible with democratic standards.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2011_jan_06-V2.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>The European Federation of Journalists (EFJ);Human Rights Watch;(CPJ);already released</elotte>
		<szavak>urges;declares;writes;a statement</szavak>
		<linkek>http://europe.ifj.org/en/articles/efj-tells-barroso-defend-free-speech-and-media-rights-in-hungary;http://www.hrw.org/en/news/2011/01/07/hungary-media-law-endangers-press-freedom;http://cpj.org/2011/01/hungary-must-repeal-repressive-new-media-law.php;http://en.rsf.org/hungary-european-parliament-urged-to-pass-31-12-2010,39200.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>6</nap>
		<cim>Financial Times publishes editorial on Hungary and op-ed by Viktor Orbán</cim>
		<szoveg>The Financial Times declaring that the new media law &quot;threatens to undermine press freedom in Hungary.&quot; Among other elements of the controversial legislation, the editorial highlights how the Media Act &quot;allows cripplingly high fines to be imposed on media organisations deemed guilty of sketchily defined offences.&quot; However, the newspaper also publishes by Prime Minister Viktor Orbán, who writes that &quot;the adoption of my country&#39;s new media law has provoked strong reactions, but they are based on total ignorance of its text.&quot; Orbán insists that the law &quot;does not contain any uniquely Hungarian regulations,&quot; and Hungary &quot;should only be obliged to change it if similar regulations in other EU member states have to be changed as well, otherwise it would be discriminatory and we would of course reject such pressure.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/06_01_2011.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Times;also publishes</elotte>
		<szavak>publishes an editorial;an op-ed</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/220509ca-19cd-11e0-b921-00144feab49a.html#axzz1BV0qDD1M;http://www.ft.com/intl/cms/s/0/478fd27e-19cd-11e0-b921-00144feab49a.html#axzz1MoGUfj5T</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>7</nap>
		<cim>Hungarian Minister: &quot;OK, we f*cked it up&quot;</cim>
		<szoveg>During a dinner with EU and media representatives in Brussels, a Hungarian minister defended the new media laws to an Economist reporter, arguing that &quot;this is central Europe, where there is anti-Semitism and anti-gypsy sentiment... the government has to protect people,&quot; but then &quot;OK, we fucked it up.&quot; After a blog post about the remark made waves domestically, the minister clarified that he had not intended criticism of the law itself, and that he was talking only about the government&#39;s presentation of its case.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2011_jan_07.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>but then</elotte>
		<szavak>conceded:</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.economist.com/blogs/charlemagne/2011/01/european_politics_0</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>7</nap>
		<cim>Havel and other former dissidents write open letter</cim>
		<szoveg>Former Czech president Vaclav Havel, former Hungarian president Arpad Goncz and other &quot;members and supporters of the democratic movements that fought against the Communist regimes in Central and Eastern Europe&quot; write an to the European Commission and Parliament and Europe&#39;s governments and political parties, expressing harsh criticism of the Hungarian government. &quot;What … many thought to be impossible, has now materialized: a full- fledged illiberal democracy inside [the EU&#39;s] own borders,&quot; they write. &quot;Hungary&#39;s government, though elected democratically, is misusing its legislative majority to methodically dismantle democracy&#39;s checks and balances, to remove constitutional constraints, and to subordinate to the will of the ruling party all branches of power, independent institutions, and the media.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/havel.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>write an</elotte>
		<szavak>open letter</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.iprotest.hu/</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>7</nap>
		<cim>Orbán: we&#39;re &quot;open to change&quot; as long as there is &quot;no campaign, no pressure&quot;</cim>
		<szoveg>European Commission President Barroso meets Prime Minister Orbán, whom he had asked to &quot;clarify&quot; the new media law, in Budapest. Afterwards, Barroso that &quot;Hungary is a democracy [..]. It is important to have no doubt about it,&quot; but he adds that &quot;it is important that the prime minister and his government take all necessary steps for this to be clear in Hungary and outside Hungary.&quot; Orbán, on his part, says: &quot;we are open to change if practice shows that there is a need for such change,&quot; but he adds that, while he was willing to listen to reasoned legal arguments, he wanted &quot;no campaign, no pressure... If there is no common sense or any reasonable argument - no change.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Afterwards, Barroso</elotte>
		<szavak>tells the press</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.economist.com/blogs/charlemagne/2011/01/barroso_budapest</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>10</nap>
		<cim>Foreign companies behind criticism of media law, says Hungarian government official</cim>
		<szoveg>In a twist on remarks of other Fidesz politicians who have called the attacks on the new media laws politically motivated, State Secretary  in a blog post that foreign companies who were forced by the new government to pay special taxes in Hungary are behind the international criticism. On January 23, the head of the Media Council and the new media regulatory authority NMHH, Annamária Szalai, similarly suggests that economic and political interests are at play behind the international criticism. On January 11, Deputy Prime Minister the Polish daily Rzeczpospolita that criticism of Hungary and its new media laws reflected a lack of trust in central and eastern European democracies, arguing that western countries find it hard to believe that strong democracies could exist in the region. He adds that the government has pledged to change the media law if the European Commission should find any part of it not in line with European law, but that it expects the media laws of all the other member states to then be examined as well.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>State Secretary;Deputy Prime Minister</elotte>
		<szavak>Zsolt Németh writes;Tibor Navracsics tells</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.businessweek.com/ap/financialnews/D9KLI7N80.htm;http://www.politics.hu/20110111/western-media-law-criticism-said-to-reflect-low-trust-of-cee-democracies</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>11</nap>
		<cim>Open hearing in European Parliament on Hungarian media law</cim>
		<szoveg>At an on freedom of the press in Hungary, hosted by the liberal ALDE group in the European Parliament, European Commissioner  that the Commission has &quot;specific concerns&quot; about the law&#39;s compliance with the AVMS Directive and, &quot;more generally, [...] the respect for freedom of expression and media pluralism.&quot; Among those giving testimony are the Hungarian writer György Konrád, who speaks of a &quot;democratura&quot; in Hungary; László Majtényi, the former Chairman of the National Radio and Television Commission, who prepared a paper with a detailed critique of the new law; and former OSCE Representative for Freedom of the Media Miklós Haraszti, who says in an interview at the event that Hungary was now &quot;the first, full-fledged il-liberal democracy inside the border lines&quot; of the EU.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wbm_KwL2ilY</video>
		<elotte>At an;European Commissioner</elotte>
		<szavak>open hearing;Neelie Kroes explains</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.theparliament.com/latest-news/article/newsarticle/hungarian-media-laws-in-focus-at-parliament-event/;http://europa.eu/rapid/pressReleasesAction.do?reference=SPEECH/11/6&amp;format=HTML&amp;aged=0&amp;language=EN&amp;guiLanguage=en</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>11</nap>
		<cim>Media Council clears radio station over Ice-T track</cim>
		<szoveg>The Media Council, which had against Tilos Radio in late December for having played a profanity-laced song by American rapper Ice-T last September, again after it drew international media attention. The council, which had argued that the lyrics could harm children and teenagers under 16, did not explain its decision to drop the case. Tilos Radio had argued that Hungarian children would not understand the complexity of the English hip-hop lyrics, though the Media Council proceedings helpfully transcribed them.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3211/2647924702_354dc2a2be.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>had;September,</elotte>
		<szavak>launched proceedings;drops the case</szavak>
		<linkek>http://blogs.wsj.com/emergingeurope/2011/01/03/language-hungary-media-council-scandalized-by-ice-t/;http://www.boston.com/ae/music/articles/2011/01/12/hungarian_radio_cleared_in_ice_t_controversy/</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>12</nap>
		<cim>Center-right group in European Parliament rejects criticisms of Hungary</cim>
		<szoveg>The center-right European People&#39;s Party (EPP) Group in the European Parliament releases rejecting &quot;all politically motivated accusations against the Hungarian government&quot; and calling &quot;on other political Groups in the European Parliament to stop making manipulative comments on the Hungarian Media Act and the Hungarian government.&quot; The day before, the Hungarian delegation to the EPP caucus &quot;all the unfounded accusations of the Hungarian Media Act,&quot; which it blamed on &quot;a lack of information and political malice.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>releases;caucus</elotte>
		<szavak>a statement;had rejected</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.eppgroup.eu/press/showpr.asp?prcontroldoctypeid=1&amp;prcontrolid=10008&amp;prcontentid=16991&amp;prcontentlg=en;http://mkdsz.hu/content/view/21063/232/</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>13</nap>
		<cim>Austrian newspapers , European Broadcasting Union, Amnesty International protest against media laws</cim>
		<szoveg>Leading Austrian newspapers, including Die Presse, Der Standard and Kurier, calling on the Hungarian government to withdraw the new media legislation. The insert, signed by the International Press Institute (IPI), Reporters without Borders and the Austrian GPA Journalists&#39; Union, warns that the new legislation constitutes a fundamental threat to press freedom and democracy by muzzling journalists and introducing censorship. On January 14, the European Broadcasting Union, an association of national broadcasters, expresses at the prospect of Hungary setting &quot;an unfortunate precedent in terms of the governance and supervision and control of the media, and restriction of pluralism.&quot; The same day, Amnesty International reiterates on the Hungarian government to change the new laws. Andrea Huber, Deputy Director of Amnesty International&#39;s Europe and Central Asia Programme, warns that &quot;facing the possibility of stringent fines or even closure, many journalists and editors are likely to choose the &#39;safe&#39; option of modifying their content.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Kurier,;expresses;reiterates</elotte>
		<szavak>carry an insert;its concern;its call</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.freemedia.at/europe/singleview/5272/;http://www.ebu.ch/en/union/news/2011/tcm_6-69670.php;http://www.amnesty.org/en/news-and-updates/protests-over-restrictive-hungarian-media-law-2011-01-14</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>13</nap>
		<cim>Hungarians &quot;like&quot; press freedom</cim>
		<szoveg>The Facebook group &quot;One Million for Press Freedom in Hungary&quot; , compared to 59,662 &quot;likes&quot; for Prime Minister Orbán. The online &quot;Proclamation for a Media Law to Ensure Basic Constitutional and Civil Rights&quot; has collected some .</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://i.imgur.com/TvfKq.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Freedom in Hungary&quot;;some</elotte>
		<szavak>hits 70,225 “likes”;5,000 signatures</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.politics.hu/20110113/hungarians-like-press-freedom-more-than-Viktor-Orban;http://www.szabadsajto.com/magyarorszag/koezlemenyek/50-proclamation</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>14</nap>
		<cim>10,000 attend demonstration against media laws</cim>
		<szoveg>In a organized by the &quot;One Million for Press Freedom in Hungary&quot; Facebook group, some ten thousand protestors gather in front of the Hungarian Parliament. Solidarity protests take place in front of the Hungarian embassies in Vienna and Berlin.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VUpb1boio50</video>
		<elotte>In a</elotte>
		<szavak>new demonstration</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.voanews.com/english/news/Thousands-Demonstrate-Against-Hungarys-Media-Law-113673314.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>17</nap>
		<cim>&#39;Extraordinary&#39; meeting in European Parliament over Hungarian media laws</cim>
		<szoveg>The Committees on Civil Liberties and on Culture of the European Parliament host a joint Extraordinary Meeting about the Hungarian media legislation. European Commissioner Kroes that she has been in touch with the Hungarian authorities &quot;to raise specific points on which the media law does not appear at first sight to be satisfactory.&quot; She mentions four of those points: the law &quot;would seem to raise a problem under the AVMS Directive because its provisions appear to apply also to media firms established in other Member States,&quot;; the law&#39;s provision on ensuring balanced information &quot;extends from the area of broadcasting, where such rules are quite common, to on-demand audiovisual media services, including for example a simple video blogger&quot;; the lack of limiting criteria in the rules on media registration; and &quot;the difficult issue of criteria for media authority independence.&quot; She adds that &quot;the Commission is also verifying the national rules implementing the AVMS Directive in other Member States, and will raise similar concerns where they are justified.&quot; Hungarian Deputy Prime Minister  Navracsics that there were many misunderstandings about the law, and &quot;a lot of people have formed a view without reading the actual text.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0BnH8Hij0_4</video>
		<elotte>Kroes;Navracsics</elotte>
		<szavak>tells the meeting;tells the meeting</szavak>
		<linkek>http://europa.eu/rapid/pressReleasesAction.do?reference=SPEECH/11/22&amp;format=HTML&amp;aged=0&amp;language=EN&amp;guiLanguage=en;http://www.politics.hu/20110118/eu-commissioner-gets-technical-on-media-law</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>18</nap>
		<cim>Hungarian government dismisses repeated OSCE criticism</cim>
		<szoveg>OSCE Representative for Freedom of the Media Dunja Mijatovic meets the Hungarian government and that the Hungarian media laws go against the country&#39;s OSCE commitments. Hungarian state secretary Zoltan Kovacs counters that the statements of the OSCE Representative have contained inaccuracies and &quot;inflammatory&quot; remarks, and adds: &quot;Right now, we do not think any changes are necessary, and every element of the law will stand the test of fundamental values in practice.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2362/5817058105_1b32a3a024_m.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>and</elotte>
		<szavak>reiterates</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.monstersandcritics.com/news/europe/news/article_1612677.php/OSCE-stands-by-criticism-of-Hungary-s-media-law</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>19</nap>
		<cim>Prime Minister Orbán clashes with European Parliament</cim>
		<szoveg>When Prime Minister Viktor Orbán to set out Hungary&#39;s priorities for its EU presidency, members of the parliament to protest against the Hungarian media laws. Many hold up signs and have taped their mouths shut. A number of speakers express their dismay; Daniel Cohn-Bendit, the co-President of the European Greens, warns Orbán that &quot;you are on the way to becoming a European Chavez.&quot; Orbán responds combatively, warning the MEPs: &quot;don&#39;t mix up criticism of Hungarian internal politics with the Hungarian EU Presidency... if you mix them up, I&#39;m ready to fight.&quot; He calls accusations questioning Hungarian democracy &quot;a slap in the face of the Hungarian people&quot; and tells Martin Schulz, the chairman of the Socialist group in the European Parliament, that he &quot;cannot go on wounding and insulting my people in this way.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wpCzA3sheVA</video>
		<elotte>Orbán;parliament</elotte>
		<szavak>addresses the European Parliament;use the occasion</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.europarl.europa.eu/pdfs/news/expert/infopress/20110119IPR11954/20110119IPR11954_en.pdf;http://www.spiegel.de/international/europe/0,1518,740400,00.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>20</nap>
		<cim>Deputy PM: European &quot;hysteria&quot; fuelled by &quot;Socialist-Liberal circles&quot; in Hungary</cim>
		<szoveg>Hungarian Deputy Prime Minister that the attacks on the media legislation have caused &quot;obvious harm&quot; to Hungary, and asserts that the &quot;hysteria&quot; over the laws in Europe is fuelled by &quot;certain Socialist-Liberal circles in Hungary.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Minister</elotte>
		<szavak>Zsolt Semjen says</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.politics.hu/20110121/media-law-hype-fuelled-by-socialists-liberals-says-deputy-pm</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>20</nap>
		<cim>US Rep to the OSCE urges Hungary to recognize concerns</cim>
		<szoveg>Ian Kelly, the U.S. Ambassador to the OSCE, tells the Permanent Council of the organization that &quot;consider the concerns raised about the law, including those cited by Ms. Mijatovic, and ensure that freedom of expression, including media freedom, is fully respected in Hungary.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>that</elotte>
		<szavak>Hungary should</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.uspolicy.be/headline/statement-ambassador-kelly-media-freedom-hungary</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>20</nap>
		<cim>German Minister of State outlines key concerns about Hungarian media law</cim>
		<szoveg>In a speech to the German Parliament about the Hungarian media legislation, Minister of State Germany&#39;s main concerns: &quot;the wide-ranging powers of the newly created media council to control the content of media output, the one-sided appointments to this body for the not inconsiderable period of nine years, the obligation to reveal sources [..], the guidelines regarding content which are defined by numerous vague legal concepts and coupled with a wide range of sanctions, as well as the obligation placed on public broadcasters to take the news from one single state news agency.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://m.blog.hu/di/diplomaci/image/werner-hoyer.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>State</elotte>
		<szavak>Werner Hoyer outlines</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.auswaertiges-amt.de/EN/Infoservice/Presse/Reden/2011/110120-Hoyer_BT_HUN_Mediengesetz.html?nn=479796</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>21</nap>
		<cim>European Commissioner threatens legal action against Hungary</cim>
		<szoveg>European Commissioner Neelie Kroes writes Minister Tibor Navracsics ,leaked on January 24, in which she expresses &quot;serious doubts as to the compatibility of Hungarian legislation with Union law&quot; and outlines three concerns about the Hungarian media laws: 1) The law&#39;s obligation on the media, including audiovisual blogs, to provide &quot;balanced&quot; coverage; 2) Its requirement of all media outlets, including the press and online media, to register with the state; 3) Its provisions that seem to extend the state&#39;s authority to impose restrictions and fines to media from other countries that can be received in Hungary. Kroes warns that the law&#39;s scope &quot;would create an unjustified restriction of the [..] fundamental right of freedom of expression and information,&quot; and gives Hungary two weeks to reply, adding that if the answer is unsatisfactory, the Commission may take legal action.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/52/Neelie_Kroes_2010-09-14.jpg/634px-Neelie_Kroes_2010-09-14.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Navracsics</elotte>
		<szavak>a letter</szavak>
		<linkek>http://cmcs.ceu.hu/files/EC_lettertoHungary_2011Jan21.pdf</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>22</nap>
		<cim>State Secretary Kovacs: Questions from European Commission are &quot;of a technical nature&quot;</cim>
		<szoveg>Hungarian State Secretary Zoltan Kovacs, acknowledging that Hungary received a letter from Commissioner Kroes, it &quot;contains questions of a technical nature rather than ones relating to freedom of speech and freedom of the press.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Kroes,</elotte>
		<szavak>insists that</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.politics.hu/20110124/ec-questions-about-media-law-technical-says-government-official</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>24</nap>
		<cim>EC spokesperson: Commissioner lacks power to insist on non-partisan media authority</cim>
		<szoveg>While European Commissioner Neelie Kroes raised four concerns about the Hungarian media laws in her speech of January 17, the letter she sent to Navracsics raises only three, omitting concerns about the partisan make-up of the new Hungarian media regulatory authority. Pressed on the issue, her spokesperson that the Commission has little leeway, as EU law &quot;does not include specific provisions on the independence of media regulatory authorities.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>spokesperson</elotte>
		<szavak>Jonathan Todd asserts</szavak>
		<linkek>http://euobserver.com/?aid=31695</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>25</nap>
		<cim>Orbán: media law meant to combat anti-Semitism, extreme right</cim>
		<szoveg>Prime Minister Orbán of the European Jewish Congress that the new media law is specifically meant to combat the anti-Semitic and racist propaganda of the extreme right.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Orbán</elotte>
		<szavak>tells a delegation</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.ejpress.org/article/news/eastern_europe/48592</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>26</nap>
		<cim>President Schmitt tells EC President freedom of speech is &quot;sacrosanct&quot; in Hungary</cim>
		<szoveg>In a meeting with European Commission President Jose Manuel Barroso in Brussels, Hungarian that &quot;The freedom of press and freedom of speech is sacrosanct in Hungary,&quot; and reiterates that the government would be ready to amend the law if &quot;needed.&quot; Barroso responds that he is &quot;sure Hungary will not miss this opportunity to show its willingness, its leadership capacity and its commitment to the European values.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5054/5511806205_feb54920d7.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Hungarian</elotte>
		<szavak>President Pal Schmitt says</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.monstersandcritics.com/news/europe/news/article_1614772.php/Press-freedom-sacrosanct-Hungarian-president-assures-Brussels</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>27</nap>
		<cim>Thousands attend new rally for media freedom</cim>
		<szoveg>A by the Facebook group &quot;One Million for Freedom of the Press in Hungary&quot; draws some 5,000 protesters to Parliament square.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>A</elotte>
		<szavak>third demonstration</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.monstersandcritics.com/news/europe/news/article_1615171.php/Thousands-join-media-law-protest-outside-Hungarian-parliament</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>27</nap>
		<cim>Council of Europe debates Hungarian democracy</cim>
		<szoveg>The Parliamentary Assembly of the Council of Europe the state of democracy in Hungary. Opening speaker Björn von Sydow suggests initiating a &quot;monitoring process&quot; on human rights in Hungary, but many right-of-center speakers defend the Hungarian government.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4136/4859613963_0dd864af70.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Europe</elotte>
		<szavak>debates</szavak>
		<linkek>http://webtv.coe.int/index.php?VODID=136</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>January</honap>
		<nap>31</nap>
		<cim>Hungary responds to European Commission, agrees to make limited amendments</cim>
		<szoveg>Responding to European Commissioner Neelie Kroes&#39;s letter from January 21, Minister Tibor Navracsics that the Hungarian government &quot;is committed to guarantee that the national regulation of media [is] in full compliance with Union law requirements.&quot; Navracsics defends the legislation on each of the three counts Kroes had raised, but nevertheless suggests some minor changes that could be made. For example, he dismisses the concern raised by Kroes that the obligation for all media, including the press, websites and non-private blogs, to register is incompatible &quot;with the principle of proportionality&quot; and would restrict freedom of expression and information, calling the claim &quot;without basis&quot;. Nevertheless, he writes, the government is open to &quot;finding other legal solutions.&quot; In response to the concern Kroes expressed over the imposition of a balanced coverage obligation on all audiovisual media service providers, he points out that the legislation did not foresee financial penalties for breaching this rule.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Navracsics</elotte>
		<szavak>writes back</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.euractiv.de/fileadmin/images/Answer_to_Mme_Neelie_Kroes.pdf</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>1</nap>
		<cim>Liberal leader in European Parliament: proposed amendments &quot;totally inadequate&quot;</cim>
		<szoveg>Guy Verhofstadt, leader of the liberal ALDE group in the European Parliament, says that &quot;the reply by the Hungarian government is totally inadequate.&quot; The Belgian politician in no EU-member country is prior registration of all media outlets required, and warns that &quot;if the Hungarian government is unable to understand the seriousness of the case and remains unwilling to make the necessary modifications,&quot; the ALDE group will press the Commission to prepare legal proceedings against Hungary. Hannes Swoboda, deputy leader of the Socialist group in the European Parliament, the amendments that are being discussed are &quot;not very satisfying.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5175/5475478629_cc061100c1.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Belgian politician;the Socialist group in the European Parliament,</elotte>
		<szavak>says that;comments that</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.alde.eu/press/press-and-release-news/press-release/article/hungarys-reply-on-media-law-is-totally-inadequate-36980/;http://www.politics.hu/20110202/media-law-casts-cloud-over-january-says-socialist-mep</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>1</nap>
		<cim>European Commissioner welcomes amended laws</cim>
		<szoveg>The the Hungarian media law to be modified &#39;&#39;within weeks rather than months,&quot; says spokesman Jonathan Todd, adding that Commissioner Neelie Kroes is &quot;eager to quickly discuss technical aspects with the Hungarian authorities in order to solve the problems raised as soon as possible.&quot; The international news media generally report the Hungarian government&#39;s letter with proposed amendments as a sign that the diplomatic crisis over the law is receding.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>The</elotte>
		<szavak>European Commission expects</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.google.com/hostednews/afp/article/ALeqM5j-I6lsDHjVdh0WPVkYxxjUo9Ue-Q?docId=CNG.14ad44f3cc93dec11aaef39a3a48949d.a31</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>1</nap>
		<cim>Socialists behind anti-Hungarian campaign, says Fidesz Dep. Chairman</cim>
		<szoveg>Fidesz deputy chairman it is &quot;clear as day that [the Socialists] lie behind the whole campaign to denigrate Hungary.&quot; András Stumpf from the conservative weekly Heti Válasz, on the other hand, writes he was &quot;not surprised by the hysteric reaction of the public and the international community,&quot; as the laws were passed &quot;without any public discussion.&quot; While insisting that freedom of speech is not in danger, the law &quot;idiotic&quot; and &quot;unnecessary.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/01_02_2011-V2.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>chairman;danger,</elotte>
		<szavak>Lajos Kósa claims;Stumpf calls</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.budapesttimes.hu/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=16579&amp;Itemid=219;http://www.xpatloop.com/news/media_crackdown_threatens_hungarys_democracy</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>1</nap>
		<cim>Council of Europe says EC should broaden review of Hungarian media laws</cim>
		<szoveg>Speaking at the end of a visit to Budapest, Council of Europe&#39;s Commissioner for Human Rights the European Commission&#39;s ongoing review of the media laws should be broadened to account for Hungary&#39;s commitments as a member state of the Council of Europe. He says concerns over the media legislation &quot;are serious and cover several areas . . . from content regulation of all media, including print and Internet press, to the use of unclear definitions for such regulation that may be subject to misinterpretation; the establishment of a politically unbalanced regulatory machinery with disproportionate powers and lack of full judicial supervision; threats to the independence of public-service broadcast media; and erosion of the protection of journalists&#39; sources, to name just a few.&quot; Hammarberg says Hungary needs to abide by Article 10 of the European Convention on Human Rights and the relevant case law of the Strasbourg Court, and should take into account the relevant Council of Europe recommendations.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/01_02_2011.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Rights</elotte>
		<szavak>Thomas Hammarberg says</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.coe.int/t/commissioner/News/2011/110201Hungary_en.asp</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>2</nap>
		<cim>NMHH decisions can be appealed in court, spokesperson says</cim>
		<szoveg>Under fire from critics who say the media laws give the new media authority NMHH too broad powers, spokesperson all decisions made by the authority can be overruled or annulled through court procedures.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://www.dunatv.hu/data/cms692575/nmhh01_119.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>spokesperson</elotte>
		<szavak>Karola Kiricsi says</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.politics.hu/20110203/media-authority-rulings-appealable-says-spokesperson</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>7</nap>
		<cim>Hungarian government promises draft amendments by the 10th</cim>
		<szoveg>After a meeting of Hungarian government and European Commission officials, Government Minister the Hungarian government has agreed to make the controversial media legislation &quot;more precise,&quot; and will present a draft of amendments by the 10th.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3PhM7w6fR0I</video>
		<elotte>Minister</elotte>
		<szavak>Zoltán Kovács says</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-12387099</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>8</nap>
		<cim>Deutsche Welle: Hungary &quot;caved into Europe-wide pressure&quot;</cim>
		<szoveg>The international German-language broadcaster that Hungary&#39;s government &quot;caved into Europe-wide pressure&quot; this week, but also notes that Viktor Orbán remained defiant at a news conference. The Hungarian Prime Minister hit back at Martin Schulz, the leader of the Socialist group in the European Parliament, who had said Hungary was becoming a dictatorship. &quot;Wow, that coming from a German,&quot; Orbán said.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>broadcaster</elotte>
		<szavak>Deutsche Welle opines</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.dw-world.de/dw/article/0,,14824823,00.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>9</nap>
		<cim>Christian online news agency vows to refuse registering with new media authority</cim>
		<szoveg>Founder Stefan Bos of BosNewsLife, an online Christian news agency, says it has  to register with the new media authority NMHH by June 30. Bos, a Dutch journalist, decries that &quot;even English language media and foreign journalists working in Hungary will now be subject to government control.&quot; On February 14, Bos writes to the Budapest Times, &quot;Orbán&#39;s Animal Farm,&quot; calling Hungary &quot;Orbánistan&quot; and announcing that &quot;as we are not planning to register, we&#39;re now awaiting sanctions.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>has;writes</elotte>
		<szavak>been ordered;a letter</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.bosnewslife.com/15354-breaking-news-bosnewslife-ordered-to-register-with-hungarys-media-authority;http://www.budapesttimes.hu/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=16787&amp;Itemid=210</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>9</nap>
		<cim>Népszabadság newspaper files suit against media law</cim>
		<szoveg>The editor of the Hungarian newspaper Népszabadság and the leader of its employees&#39; association against the new media law with Hungary&#39;s constitutional court, claiming that the law curbed press freedom and freedom of opinion in 16 areas and questioning the constitutionality of the broad powers conferred on the new Media Council. The complaints include the new media authority&#39;s supervision over print media, its powers to impose fines and regulate new media, and the requirement that reporting in the printed media must be balanced.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>association</elotte>
		<szavak>file a complaint</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.politics.hu/20110210/daily-turns-to-top-court-over-media-law</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>10</nap>
		<cim>Miklos Haraszti: Agreement with European Commission is insufficient</cim>
		<szoveg>Miklós Haraszti, the former OSCE Representative on Freedom of the Media, publishes an of &quot;the main deficiencies of the new Hungarian media laws, at least with regard to the safeguards of media freedom and pluralism, laid down in Article 11 of the EU Charter of Basic Rights,&quot; which takes into account the agreement between the Hungarian government and the European Commission. He concludes with a list of recommended steps the Hungarian government should take, which go &quot;far beyond the changes covered in the agreement with the European Commission.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://i.imgur.com/GaSJc.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>publishes an</elotte>
		<szavak>updated analysis</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.iwm.at/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=435&amp;Itemid=231</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>10</nap>
		<cim>European Commission: Hungarian authorities &quot;making every effort&quot; to comply with EU legislation</cim>
		<szoveg>The that the group of specialists who took part in discussions with media specialists from the European Commission have sent their written proposals, &quot;clarifying the Hungarian media legislation,&quot; in response to the concerns raised by Commissioner Neelie Kroes. The government adds that it remains &quot;open to further consultation.&quot; The day after, European Commission spokesman that &quot;the Hungarian authorities are making every effort&quot; to ensure that their law complies with EU law, but adds that lawyers would have to determine if the changes would bring Hungary into full compliance. Neither the Commission nor the Hungarian government reveals the contents of the draft amendments. The Hungarian Socialists say the text should be made public &quot;in its entirety and without delay.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>The;spokesman</elotte>
		<szavak>Hungarian government announces;Jonathan Todd confirms</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.kormany.hu/en/ministry-of-public-administration-and-justice/news/written-proposals-have-been-finalised-for-consideration-by-the-european-commission;http://www.forexpros.com/news/general-news/hungary-making-every-effort-on-media-law-eu-commission-194194</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>14</nap>
		<cim>Prime Minister Orbán: &quot;Brussels is not Moscow&quot;</cim>
		<szoveg>In to the Hungarian Parliament, Prime Minister Orbán tells lawmakers the media law has &quot;served as pretense to launch an attack on the country&quot; and &quot;nobody will mop the floor with this government the way they have done with our inept and hapless predecessors.&quot; Alluding to the Soviet Union&#39;s failed dominion over Hungary during communism, Orbán proclaimed: &quot;Brussels is no Moscow.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/2/27/EPP_Summit_March_2011_Viktor_Orb%C3%A1n.jpg/760px-EPP_Summit_March_2011_Viktor_Orb%C3%A1n.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>In</elotte>
		<szavak>a fiery speech</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.gulf-times.com/site/topics/article.asp?cu_no=2&amp;item_no=416155&amp;version=1&amp;template_id=39&amp;parent_id=21</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>16</nap>
		<cim>European leaders react to media law amendments</cim>
		<szoveg>The proposed amendments to Hungary&#39;s media laws receive from European politicians. Martin Schulz, leader of the Socialist and Democrats group in the European Parliament, says the proposed amendments omit key issues, such as the composition of the Media Council, and calls Neelie Kroes&#39; response &quot;far from satisfactory.&quot; Rebecca Harms, co-president of the Green group, says the amendments are welcome, but &quot;ignore the core provisions of the media law that will undermine media freedom in Hungary: notably, the politicised media supervision authority.&quot; She argues that the law still violates the Charter of Fundamental Rights, and calls on the European Commission to &quot;continue to push for the complete overhaul or withdrawal of the law on this basis.&quot; According to Dunja Mijatovic, the OSCE Representative on Freedom of the Media, &quot;if the Hungarian government is now going to change the laws, then the media legislation needs to be amended also in light of protecting OSCE commitments.&quot; But Joseph Daul, chairman of the center-right EPP group in the European Parliament, says that the agreement &quot;proves that the wave of political attacks on the law was premature and unjustified.&quot;Liberal leader Guy Verhofstadt comments: &quot;it&#39;s going in the right direction, but whether it&#39;s enough, I can&#39;t tell.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>receive</elotte>
		<szavak>a mixed response</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.euractiv.com/en/future-eu/brussels-happy-hungarys-pledges-media-law-news-502238</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>16</nap>
		<cim>European Commissioner Kroes presents agreement on media law amendments</cim>
		<szoveg>The European Parliament on the Hungarian media law, to be followed by a vote on a resolution by the liberal, socialist, green and left-socialist groups. The vote is delayed after European Commissioner Neelie Kroes appears with the text in hand of the amendments proposed by the Hungarian government. Kroes claims the amendments would address all the issues she had raised. She rebuffs criticism that the amendments would not address the question of the independence of the new Hungarian media regulatory bodies. According to Kroes, the Commission lacks the authority to oblige EU countries to guarantee the independence of national regulatory authorities, since a proposal to include such an authority in the AVMS Directive had been removed by the EU Member States.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oZSiQldKQiI</video>
		<elotte>Parliament</elotte>
		<szavak>convenes a debate</szavak>
		<linkek>http://europa.eu/rapid/pressReleasesAction.do?reference=MEMO/11/89</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>17</nap>
		<cim>Media freedom groups say the proposed media law amendments are &#39;inadequate&#39;</cim>
		<szoveg>International media-freedom watchdog Reporters Without Borders  calling the European Commission&#39;s response &quot;inadequate,&quot; and claiming the Commission has been &quot;strangely silent&quot; about the new Media Council&#39;s excessive regulatory powers. The (API-IPA) declares that the new media legislation &quot;continues to endanger media freedom despite the welcome but very limited amendments,&quot; and reiterates its call for the laws to be rescinded. A day later, the European Federation of Journalists (EFJ) claims the rather than the &quot;cosmetic changes&quot; proposed by the European Commission.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Borders;regulatory powers. The;claims the</elotte>
		<szavak>issues a statement;International Press Association;laws require &quot;radical surgery&quot;</szavak>
		<linkek>http://en.rsf.org/hungary-european-commission-response-to-17-02-2011,39575.html;http://www.api-ipa.eu/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=186&amp;Itemid=35;http://europe.ifj.org/en/articles/efj-calls-for-radical-surgery-not-cosmetics-on-hungary-s-media-law</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>17</nap>
		<cim>Media Council hints on interpretation of &#39;public morality&#39; and &#39;human dignity&#39;</cim>
		<szoveg>The Media Council has hinted how it may interpret what critics say are unclear provisions on infringements to &quot;public morality&quot; and &quot;human dignity,&quot; . In to a letter to the Hungarian Wives&#39; Association, the Council wrote that &quot;a wife&#39;s most natural profession is creating life and being a mother, which can be fulfilled in a family. . . That&#39;s why it would be inevitably necessary on the media&#39;s part to observe female dignity and to endorse the virtues of motherhood, family and marriage.&quot; It added that it would be unacceptable for the media to &quot;spread an impermissibly positive view about martial infidelity, divorce, free sexual life, [and] pornography.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://i.imgur.com/zBXfM.gif</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>&quot;human dignity,&quot;</elotte>
		<szavak>The Wall Street Journal reports</szavak>
		<linkek>http://blogs.wsj.com/emergingeurope/2011/02/17/hungary-to-leave-controversial-media-laws-core-intact</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>17</nap>
		<cim>Mixed reception of proposed media law amendments</cim>
		<szoveg>Critics whether the amendments to the media laws will have any substantive effect. &quot;Four paragraphs will be amended in a law that contains 226,&quot; says Népszabadság deputy editor-in- chief Gabor Horvath, adding: &quot;It is the same people who drafted the law who will enforce it, the same who will allocate frequencies; they are the ones who will decide what is illegal or not and they will be the ones to inflict punishments.&quot; While the German FAZ newspaper concludes that Orbán &quot;scored a victory&quot; with the amended media law, France 24 reports that &quot;Budapest bows to EU on controversial media law.&quot; The New York Times runs the headline &quot;Hungary Tones Down Media Law to End E.U. Conflict.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Critics</elotte>
		<szavak>remain skeptical</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.eubusiness.com/news-eu/hungary-politics.8nt/</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>22</nap>
		<cim>U.S. Ambassador writes op-ed on freedom of expression</cim>
		<szoveg>Hungarian daily newspaper Népszabadság publishes an op-ed on the state of free expression in the world, in which she welcomes the Hungarian government&#39;s agreement with the European Commission on amendments to the media laws and hails the &quot;vigorous public debate&quot; on the subject in Hungary.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://i.imgur.com/ahyym.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>op-ed</elotte>
		<szavak>by U.S. Ambassador Eleni Tsakopoulos Kounalakis</szavak>
		<linkek>http://hungary.usembassy.gov/kounalakis_freedom.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>23</nap>
		<cim>Hungarian Civil Liberties Union addresses detailed critique to European Commissioner Kroes</cim>
		<szoveg>In a the Hungarian Civil Liberties Union (HCLU) expresses &quot;grave concern&quot; over the narrow scope of the proposed amendments and urges Kroes to push for additional changes. The group notes that Kroes restricted her investigation to application of the Audiovisual Media Services Directive, &quot;without analyzing the Hungarian media legislation from the point of view of freedom of the press and that of the media, which are considered to be fundamental values of the European Union, [or] with regard to further EU law on the field of e-commerce, competition and info-communication.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://i.imgur.com/k1shA.gif</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>a</elotte>
		<szavak>letter to European Commissioner Neelie Kroes,</szavak>
		<linkek>http://tasz.hu/files/tasz/imce/kroes_letter_0223.pdf</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>23</nap>
		<cim>Media law amendments submitted to Parliament</cim>
		<szoveg>The governing Fidesz party which the government reached an agreement on with the European Commission to Parliament. The bill submitted does not, however, remove the prohibition against causing &quot;direct or indirect offense&quot; to minorities or majorities, one of the changes agreed on with the Commission.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>party</elotte>
		<szavak>submits the amendments to the media legislation</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.politics.hu/20110224/hungarian-govt-submits-media-law-amendment-to-parliament-in-grudging-concession-to-eu</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>25</nap>
		<cim>Council of Europe: media laws fail to meet international free press standards</cim>
		<szoveg>Thomas Hammarberg, the Council of Europe&#39;s Commissioner for Human Rights, detailing six areas in which Hungary&#39;s media legislation fails to meet Council of Europe media freedom standards. He says Hungary &quot;should abide by its commitments as a member state of the Council of Europe and make the most of the organization&#39;s expertise in the fields of freedom of expression and media independence and pluralism.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Rights,</elotte>
		<szavak>issues an opinion</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.coe.int/t/commissioner/News/2011/110225MediaHungary_en.asp</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>28</nap>
		<cim>OSCE sends Hungarian government legal analysis, detailed recommendations</cim>
		<szoveg>OSCE Representative on Freedom of the Media Dunja Mijatovic submits of the media laws to the Hungarian government, including detailed recommendations for bringing thelegislation in compliance with OSCE commitments. The analysis indicates that the media laws &quot;should be changed in many respects,&quot; and &quot;several provisions of the current laws fail to safeguard media pluralism and the free flow of information.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2362/5817058105_1b32a3a024.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>submits</elotte>
		<szavak>a legal analysis</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.osce.org/fom/75990</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>February</honap>
		<nap>28</nap>
		<cim>Columbia Journalism Review: &quot;Hungarian Chill&quot;</cim>
		<szoveg>&quot;The new Hungarian media law is a patchwork of the worst practices in the EU, with some extra limits on freedom of the press,&quot; Éva Simon of the Hungarian Civil Liberties Union (HCLU) tells the . The HCLU has filed a petition with the country&#39;s top court to strike provisions of the media legislation which it considers to violate domestic and international laws protecting free press, including Article 61 in Hungary&#39;s Constitution, Article 11 of the EU Charter of Fundamental Rights, and Article 10 of the European Convention on Human Rights.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>tells the</elotte>
		<szavak>Columbia Journalism Review</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.cjr.org/behind_the_news/hungarian_chill.php?page=all</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>1</nap>
		<cim>MEP calls for a new EU media freedom watchdog</cim>
		<szoveg>At a hearing of the European Parliament&#39;s media intergroup, German member of the parliament Jorgo Chatzimarkakis to establish an EU-wide watchdog to monitor press freedom. Chatzimarkakis says the controversy over Hungary&#39;s media law and ongoing ownership issues in Italy demonstrate the need to establish such a unit. Tibor Kovacs, president of the Hungarian Publishers&#39; Association, tells the hearing that the Hungarian media laws had brought &quot;profound changes&quot; to the print media, adding that it was &quot;extremely urgent to amend those laws concerning the written press.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2011_mar_01-V2.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Chatzimarkakis</elotte>
		<szavak>urges the European Commission</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.theparliament.com/latest-news/article/newsarticle/eu-commission-urged-to-set-up-press-freedom-watchdog/</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>1</nap>
		<cim>Free speech group &#39;alarmed&#39; by amended media laws</cim>
		<szoveg>Article 19, the London-based free speech group, to the Hungarian media law package, but is &quot;alarmed by the fact that many problematic provisions... remain unchanged.&quot; The organization details areas in which the amended laws still fall short of international freedom of expression standards.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2011_mar_01.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>group,</elotte>
		<szavak>welcomes the proposed amendments</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.article19.org/pdfs/reports/hungary-article-19-calls-for-comprehensive-media-law-reform.pdf</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>2</nap>
		<cim>US-based Internet freedom think tank: Hungarian media laws limit press freedom</cim>
		<szoveg>The Center for Democracy and Technology (CDT), a Washington D.C.-based internet freedom think tank, releases an of the new Hungarian media legislation, and concludes that the proposed amendments are &quot;largely cosmetic and insubstantial&quot; and &quot;fail to address several of the more problematic provisions in the Acts.&quot; The review cites the legislation&#39;s main problems as its &quot;overbroad jurisdictional scope&quot; and &quot;the creation of an extensive, complex, and overlapping bureaucratic web of administrative authorities, ultimately answerable to the Prime Minister, with far-reaching powers to control the media.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2011_mar_02.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>releases an</elotte>
		<szavak>updated legal analysis</szavak>
		<linkek>http://cmcs.ceu.hu/files/CDT%20Analysis%20Amendments%20to%20Hungarian%20Media%20Laws.pdf</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>3</nap>
		<cim>Members of European Parliament alarmed at state of press freedom in Hungary, Europe</cim>
		<szoveg>At a press freedom conference in Brussels, members of the European Parliament and media professionals at the rapidly deteriorating state of press freedom in Hungary, Romania and Bulgaria, but also Italy and France. Participants described the media freedom situation in those countries as &quot;extremely dangerous&quot; and called for a stronger response by the European Commission.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>professionals</elotte>
		<szavak>express alarm</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.euractiv.com/en/future-eu/media-experts-urge-reconquest-press-freedom-news-502738</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>7</nap>
		<cim>Hungarian Parliament passes media law amendments</cim>
		<szoveg>Hungarian lawmakers to two of the controversial media laws they passed last year, to take into account four issues which the European Commission considered to breach EU directives. European Commissioner Neelie Kroes praises the Hungarian government for its &quot;constructive stance,&quot; after noting that &quot;in the implementation, we still need to be quite active in monitoring what is at stake.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>lawmakers</elotte>
		<szavak>pass amendments</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.reuters.com/article/2011/03/07/us-hungary-media-vote-idUSTRE7265RN20110307</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>7</nap>
		<cim>Media law amendments get mixed reviews in foreign press</cim>
		<szoveg>Amendments to Hungary&#39;s media laws passed by parliament today are met with mixed opinions abroad. &quot;Hungary has bowed to pressure from the European Commission,&quot; writes Deutsche Welle. &quot;Buckling under the pressure, the parliament struck and softened the law&#39;s most contentious points&quot;, Foreign Policy. But German press agency that key criticisms of the legislation remain largely unaddressed; for example, that &quot;a new Media Councilstaffed exclusively by government nominees with nine- year tenure [is] solely responsible for interpreting vague legal requirements.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>contentious points&quot;,;agency</elotte>
		<szavak>opined;DPA notes</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.foreignpolicy.com/articles/2011/03/09/new_europe_new_problems?page=full;http://www.monstersandcritics.com/news/europe/news/article_1624281.php/Hungary-waters-down-media-law-but-EU-to-remain-vigilant</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>7</nap>
		<cim>Cartoonists unhappy with new media laws</cim>
		<szoveg>Three Hungarian editorial cartoonists about how the media law will impact their ability to express opinions, arguing that &quot;assaulting the &#39;human dignity&#39; of politicians is what editorial cartoonists do for a living.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2011_mar_07-V2.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>cartoonists</elotte>
		<szavak>speak up</szavak>
		<linkek>http://blog.cartoonmovement.com/2011/03/hungarian-cartooonists-under-fire-from-repressive-new-law.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>8</nap>
		<cim>OSCE not satisfied by media law amendments</cim>
		<szoveg>Hungary&#39;s amended media legislation OSCE press freedom commitments, says OSCE Representative on Freedom of the Media Dunja Mijatovic. &quot;The law vests unusually broad powers in the politically homogeneous Media Authority and Media Council, enabling them to control content of all media,&quot; says Mijatovic. &quot;The legislation regulates broadcast, print and online media content based on identical principles. It leaves key terms undefined. It requires all media to be registered with the Media Authority. It punishes violations with high fines. It fails to guarantee the political independence of public service media.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>legislation</elotte>
		<szavak>still violates</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.osce.org/fom/75999</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>9</nap>
		<cim>President European Parliament: EU will monitor implementation of media laws</cim>
		<szoveg>President of the European Parliament the media law amendments and says the process shows the EU is working effectively. He adds that the EU will monitor the Hungarian government&#39;s implementation of the media law.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4149/5099853902_c86d7371ab.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Parliament</elotte>
		<szavak>Jerzy Buzek welcomes</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.politics.hu/20110310/eu-to-monitor-implementation-of-media-law-says-ep-president</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>10</nap>
		<cim>European Parliament passes resolution urging Hungary to further review media laws</cim>
		<szoveg>The European Parliament passes criticizing the limited scope of the amendments Hungary passed to its controversial media laws. The resolution calls on Hungary to further review the media law in order to &quot;restore the independence of media governance and halt state interference with freedom of expression.&quot; The resolution also urges the government to take into account the recommendations from the OSCE, the Council of Europe and the Parliament and to repeal &quot;the law or those elements thereof that are found to be incompatible . . . with the letter or spirit of the Treaties or EU law, the Charter of Fundamental Rights or the ECHR.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ubz9M3uEO34</video>
		<elotte>passes</elotte>
		<szavak>a resolution</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.europarl.europa.eu/sides/getDoc.do?pubRef=-//EP//TEXT+TA+P7-TA-2011-0094+0+DOC+XML+V0//EN</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>11</nap>
		<cim>International journalist groups call for more changes to media laws</cim>
		<szoveg>&quot;The Hungarian government is merely paying lip service to upholding fundamental principles of press freedom enshrined in the European Union,&quot; writes the Committee to Protect Journalists (CPJ) in a statement on the newly passed amendments to the media law. The CPJ argues fundamental changes are still needed to bring the media laws in line with the EU&#39;s Charter of Fundamental Rights. The International Press Institute (IPI) and Reporters without Borders also renewed objections to the amendments. &quot;While we welcome the fact that some changes have been made, a number of areas of concern remain,&quot; Press Freedom Manager Anthony Mills wrote in released on March 9. &quot;Unless they too are addressed, the legislation still constitutes a potential threat to press freedom.&quot; On March 8, Reporters Without Borders that despite &quot;positive movement on some of the worst aspects of the legislation, the core of the problem remains, since the composition and attributions of the all-powerful Media Council remain unchanged.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Mills wrote in;On March 8, Reporters Without Borders</elotte>
		<szavak>a statement;claimed</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.freemedia.at/europe/singleview/5382/;http://en.rsf.org/hongrie-hungary-s-media-law-is-08-03-2011,39721.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>15</nap>
		<cim>Largest media freedom demonstration to date draws 30,000</cim>
		<szoveg>An estimated against the media law in the largest free press demonstration to date, organized by the Facebook group &quot;One Million for the Freedom of Press in Hungary.&quot; Adam Michnik, Polish newspaper editor and former dissident, tells the crowd &quot;there is no place for censorship&quot; in a democracy. The demonstration, held on the anniversary of the 1848 revolution, is the largest protest by civic groups since 1989. The Economist comments that the demonstration marks &quot;a revival of liberal values in Hungary&#39;s public sphere.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Eoo4B4kcJ_4</video>
		<elotte>estimated;crowd</elotte>
		<szavak>30,000 protestors demonstrate;(panorama view)</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.economist.com/blogs/easternapproaches/2011/03/protest_hungary;http://freepress.blog.hu/2011/03/15/one_million_on_the_road_of_free_press;http://www.szigetiadam.hu/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/marcius15sajtoszabadsapanorama7.swf</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>16</nap>
		<cim>Media Council head says new laws in line with EU media regulations</cim>
		<szoveg>Annamária Szalai, head of the Media Council and the new media regulatory authority NMHH, says the media laws conform to EU media regulation standards and the country&#39;s &quot;uncontrollable and chaotic&quot; public-service media. She claims that the laws aim to create new broadcasting standards and provide a legal framework for the growing convergence between media providers and news networks. Regarding sanctions against media, Szalai says the goal is &quot;prevention rather than punishment.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>regulation standards and</elotte>
		<szavak>will renew</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.politics.hu/20110317/media-authority-head-says-law-conforms-to-european-union-guidelines</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>18</nap>
		<cim>Amnesty International calls for additional amendments</cim>
		<szoveg>In to the Hungarian government on the new media legislation, Amnesty International argues that despite the amendments, the new media legislation still represents &quot;a threat to the right to freedom of expression,&quot; by creating &quot;a system of media content regulation and compulsory media registration,&quot; and &quot;introduces a powerful Media Authority without ensuring the necessary safeguards that these instruments will not lead to interference with internationally protected human rights.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>In</elotte>
		<szavak>a briefing</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.amnesty.org/en/library/asset/EUR27/004/2011/en/3af2e47c-a909-48d4-ad31-45f873ee892b/eur270042011en.pdf</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>22</nap>
		<cim>Amendments to Media Act and &quot;Media Constitution&quot; become law</cim>
		<szoveg>Amendments to the two most controversial media laws passed by Hungarian parliament last year, passed by the Hungarian parliament after negotiations with the European Commission, become law. The new media regulatory authority, the NMHH, provides English translations of the modified , the Media Act, and , the so-called the &quot;Media Constitution&quot;.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>modified;and</elotte>
		<szavak>Law 185/2010;Law 104/2010</szavak>
		<linkek>http://nmhh.hu/dokumentum.php?cid=26536;http://cmcs.ceu.hu/files/act_CIV_of_2010_press_freedom_and_fr_of_media_content.pdf</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>22</nap>
		<cim>Analysis argues that Hungarian media law curtails press freedom</cim>
		<szoveg>The South East European Network for Professionalization of Media (SEENPM) releases of the new Hungarian media legislation showing that the laws substantially curb freedom of the press in Hungary.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://i.imgur.com/TsExI.gif</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>releases</elotte>
		<szavak>an analysis</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.seemo.org/hungary/files/Bayer_Media%20Law_IFEX_ENfinal220311.pdf</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>25</nap>
		<cim>European Commission comes up short, says human rights expert</cim>
		<szoveg>Human Rights Watch researcher Amanda McRae the European Commission&#39;s response to the Hungarian media laws in an op-ed in the EU Observer. &quot;The European Commission deserves credit for acting swiftly to press Hungary to abide by EU standards,&quot; she writes, &quot;but the EU also bears some responsibility for the incomplete nature of the reforms.&quot; Commissioner Neelie Kroes failed to ensure that amendments fully addressed the concerns she had raised in her initial, strongly-worded letter to the Hungarian government, according to McRae.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>McRae</elotte>
		<szavak>criticizes</szavak>
		<linkek>http://euobserver.com/9/32065</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>30</nap>
		<cim>Hungarian-American business man blames the left for &#39;international witch-hunt&#39;</cim>
		<szoveg>In an op-ed in the , Hungarian-American businessman George F. Hemingway claims that multi-national corporations, left-wing intellectuals and the ruling business elite, &quot;sensing danger to their interests,&quot; are purposefully undermining the international credibility of the Hungarian government and using the foreign media as &quot;a willing tool.&quot; The old media laws were &quot;much in need of change,&quot; he writes, decrying how the new legislation has been used by the opposition to launch an &quot;international witch-hunt.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>the</elotte>
		<szavak>Budapest Times</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.budapesttimes.hu/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=17198&amp;Itemid=223</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>March</honap>
		<nap>31</nap>
		<cim>European Greens host public debate about democracy, media laws in Hungary</cim>
		<szoveg>At the 14th European Green Party Council meeting, held in Budapest, the Green group in the European Parliament hosts a public debate on the state of democracy in Hungary. Daniel Cohn-Bendit, co-president of the Green group in the European Parliament, and Miklós Haraszti, former OSCE Representative for Freedom of the Media, offer of the new media legislation.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oZdvGnsEwL4</video>
		<elotte>offer</elotte>
		<szavak>harsh criticism</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.greenmediabox.eu/archive/2011/03/31/crossroads/</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>April</honap>
		<nap>5</nap>
		<cim>UN rep &quot;shocked&quot; by government stance on media</cim>
		<szoveg>At a press conference in Budapest, United Nations Special Rapporteur on Freedom of Expression Frank La Rue says he was &quot;shocked&quot; by some of the views about the new media laws he heard during his meetings, . &quot;Different government officials were speaking with full honesty and speaking their mind, but it does seem to me that there is a framework of control. I think this is very dangerous.&quot; His (link to Word doc) highlights six concerns, including insufficient guarantees to ensure the independence of the Media Authority, excessive fines and sanctions, the application of the laws to all types of media, including the Internet, and lacking protection of journalistic sources.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>meetings,;dangerous.&quot; His</elotte>
		<szavak>Bloomberg reports;end-of-mission statement</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2011-04-05/un-rapporteur-shocked-by-media-view-of-hungarian-officials.html;http://www2.ohchr.org/english/issues/opinion/docs/2011-04-05_Hungary_Freedex_EndMission.doc</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>April</honap>
		<nap>6</nap>
		<cim>Hungary Press Freedom website launched</cim>
		<szoveg>The South and East Europe Media Organisation (SEEMO), a network of editors, journalists and media executives, dedicated to press freedom-related developments in Hungary.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>media executives,</elotte>
		<szavak>launches a website</szavak>
		<linkek>http://hungarypressfreedom.org</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>April</honap>
		<nap>12</nap>
		<cim>Public broadcaster accused of manipulating news report</cim>
		<szoveg>Hungarian opposition party LMP to investigate a &quot;clearly manipulative&quot; news report by the Hungarian public broadcaster MTV on Daniel Cohn-Bendit, the co-president of the Green group in European Parliament who expressed fierce criticism of Hungary&#39;s new media laws. According to the LMP, the report was edited to make it appear as if he had abandoned a news conference in Budapest on April 1 in order to avoid a question about past allegations of pedophilia, but news portal Index.hu obtained the full recording of the press conference, which revealed that he responded to the question. Index.hu also reported that the journalist who made the report, Daniel Papp, was (link in French) to editor-in-chief at the new centralised public service media institution, MTVA. Papp, who previously worked for the far-right Jobbik party, will work with recently appointed news director Gabor Elő. Both previously worked for the conservative Echo TV.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>LMP;Papp, was</elotte>
		<szavak>calls on the Media Council;subsequently promoted</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.budapesttimes.hu/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=17346&amp;Itemid=220;http://www.jfb.hu/node/1753</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>April</honap>
		<nap>13</nap>
		<cim>Mass lay-offs planned at public broadcasters</cim>
		<szoveg>A third of Hungary&#39;s public service media journalists will be laid off this year, of Hungary&#39;s new, centralized public service media institution, the MTVA. Meanwhile, the head of the Independent News Agency (FH) argues that plans for the national news agency MTI to supply public media with centrally prepared news bulletins constitutes a violation of the principle of free competition, and says he will take the case to the European Commission if necessary.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>this year,</elotte>
		<szavak>says the director</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.budapesttimes.hu/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=17345&amp;Itemid=26</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>April</honap>
		<nap>15</nap>
		<cim>Thousands protest against new constitution</cim>
		<szoveg>Facebook-organized demonstrations as Parliament prepares to vote on a new constitution.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>demonstrations</elotte>
		<szavak>continue</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.reuters.com/article/2011/04/15/hungary-constitution-idUSLDE73E1WW20110415</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>April</honap>
		<nap>15</nap>
		<cim>Government says press freedom has limits</cim>
		<szoveg>Zoltán Kovács, State Secretary for Government Communications, says that the government freedoms of the press and freedom of opinion, but that &quot;local peculiarities&quot; need to be taken into account when those principles are applied.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>the government</elotte>
		<szavak>supports</szavak>
		<linkek>http://finance.yahoo.com/news/Rights-expert-still-critical-apf-579784269.html?x=0&amp;.v=2</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>April</honap>
		<nap>18</nap>
		<cim>Hungary passes new constitution</cim>
		<szoveg>Hungarian Parliament  passes a new constitution in a vote along party lines. The far-right Jobbik party votes against the constitution, while the other opposition parties boycott the vote, saying that the new text eliminates the country&#39;s system of checks and balances and represents only the views of the governing Fidesz party. From the perspective of Fidesz, however, the , the party&#39;s election victory last year constituted &quot;a revolution at the voting booths,&quot; and netted not just a two-thirds parliamentary majority but a mandate to overhaul the country&#39;s economy and legal foundations. The new constitution stipulates that numerous issues, including family policy and the tax and pension systems, will be specified in separate laws which can only be amended by a two thirds majority. The Hungarian Civil Liberties Union (HCLU) criticizes the new constitution, claiming it discriminates against those who do not share Christian-conservative values and enshrines the government&#39;s ideology into a legal doctrine that is devised to be extremely hard to amend.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>however, the</elotte>
		<szavak>Wall Street Journal writes</szavak>
		<linkek>http://blogs.wsj.com/emergingeurope/2011/04/18/hungary-passes-new-constitution-amid-concerns/</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>April</honap>
		<nap>18</nap>
		<cim>UN Secretary-General weighs in on media laws</cim>
		<szoveg>During a visit to Hungary, UN Secretary-General Ban Ki-Moon for its &quot;remarkable&quot; transformation from communism to democracy, but adds that Hungary&#39;s new media legislation should be &quot;consistent with the legacy of your own fight for freedom and in tune with concerns in your neighborhood and around the world.&quot; Ki-Moon claims that &quot;freedom of expression and the media are essential foundations for any healthy democracy.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3345/3237185352_8efd00a00d.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Ki-Moon</elotte>
		<szavak>praises the country</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.un.org/apps/news/story.asp?NewsID=38139</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>April</honap>
		<nap>19</nap>
		<cim>German, Hungarian foreign ministries trade jabs</cim>
		<szoveg>Hungarian foreign minister Zsolt Németh not to interfere in Hungary&#39;s domestic affairs, in response to German Deputy Foreign Minister Werner Hoyer&#39;s statement that Germany is &quot;observing the developments in Hungary with great attention and not without concern.&quot; Hoyer criticized the new media legislation as incompatible with EU values, and added that &quot;our worries over the media law are made worse, not better, by the adoption of the constitution.&quot; Németh responds by calling Hoyer&#39;s remarks &quot;incomprehensible and unacceptable,&quot; and rejects Hoyer&#39;s reference to the media legislation as &quot;particularly unacceptable.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Németh</elotte>
		<szavak>warns Germany</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.upi.com/Top_News/Special/2011/04/19/Berlin-blasts-Hungary-for-new-constitution/UPI-50981303228193/</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>April</honap>
		<nap>25</nap>
		<cim>Civil rights groups: new constitution weakens right to access to information</cim>
		<szoveg>The new Hungarian constitution replaces the independent Data Protection and Freedom of Information Commissioner with an administrative authority with undetermined powers, according to human rights groups. Four organizations, including the Hungarian Civil Liberties Union (HCLU) and the South East Network for Professionalization of the Media (SEENPM), warn that this change could the right to access to information. &quot;This move is a way to bring an immediate end to the independence of the existing information commissioner and replace him with a more subservient authority,&quot; says Helen Darbishire of Access Info Europe.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>this change could</elotte>
		<szavak>dramatically weaken</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.seenpm.org/new/index.php?id=97</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>May</honap>
		<nap>2</nap>
		<cim>Hungary slides in Freedom House ranking</cim>
		<szoveg>Hungary&#39;s ranking in an annual global press freedom report by international human rights organization Freedom House 65th,, from 40th in 2010. The report says that Hungary&#39;s slide in the ranking is a result of &quot;the government&#39;s efforts to consolidate control over the country&#39;s independent institutions, including the creation of a new media council dominated by the ruling party that has the ability to impose large fines on broadcast, print, and online media outlets.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>http://i.imgur.com/XfY5y.gif</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>House</elotte>
		<szavak>drops to</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.freedomhouse.org/images/File/fiw/FIW_2011_Booklet.pdf</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>May</honap>
		<nap>5</nap>
		<cim>Council of Europe Commissioner calls EU-Hungary media amendment deal &quot;unfortunate&quot;</cim>
		<szoveg>Council of Europe Commissioner for Human Rights Thomas Hammarberg  that the deal between the Hungarian government and the European Commission to amend provisions in the media laws was &quot;unfortunate,&quot; since the appearance of Brussels giving its “blessing” to the amended law undermined the message of his own office&#39;s report, which found there were still &quot;serious flaws&quot; in the legislation.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>Hammarberg</elotte>
		<szavak>tells Euractiv.com</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.euractiv.com/en/future-eu/human-rights-commissioner-europe-leaders-betray-basic-principles-interview-504566</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>May</honap>
		<nap>11</nap>
		<cim>UN Human Rights Council questions Hungary over media law</cim>
		<szoveg>Members of the UN Human Rights Council from the UK, Germany, Belgium and Holland over Hungary&#39;s media legislation. US delegate John C. Mariz calls the new laws &quot;a departure from the Hungarian tradition of multi-party appointments to the media regulatory board, which raise concerns over strict regulation and limitations on freedom of expression.&quot; At the same time, representatives ask what measures Hungary plans to take to combat hate speech. Germany&#39;s human rights commissioner Markus Loening a German newspaper beforehand that the Hungarian media legislation was still full of &quot;rules that contravene international standards.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2011_maj_11.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>and Holland;Loening</elotte>
		<szavak>express concerns;had told</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.journalism.co.uk/news/hungary-faces-criticism-over-media-law-from-un-humanrights-council/s2/a544108/;http://www.expatica.com/de/news/german-news/germany-to-grill-hungary-over-new-laws-at-un-meet_147626.html</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>May</honap>
		<nap>30</nap>
		<cim>Independent news agency gives up</cim>
		<szoveg>The owners of independent news agency FH announce that it. The company, which produced some 150-200 broadcast-ready news items per day but never turned a profit, faced additional trouble now that the new media legislation tasked national news agency MTI with providing its news for free, to commercial as well as public media.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>img/2011_maj_30.jpg</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>that it</elotte>
		<szavak>would close</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.budapesttimes.hu/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=19335&amp;Itemid=163</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>June</honap>
		<nap>2</nap>
		<cim>UN Rapporteur on freedom of expression returns to Hungary</cim>
		<szoveg>Frank La Rue, The UN Special Rapporteur on freedom of opinion and expression, makes to Budapest for talks with the Hungarian government, and notes that Hungary&#39;s lawmakers disregarded several of the recommendations he&#39;d made in April. He  questioned the independence of the new Media Council, and said it could only become a creditable body when its decisions reflected the views of the opposition and civil society as well as the government parties.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>makes</elotte>
		<szavak>a return visit</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.politics.hu/20110603/un-rapporteur-raises-concern-over-media-independence/</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>June</honap>
		<nap>8</nap>
		<cim>Independent talk radio station under threat</cim>
		<szoveg>The new Hungarian media authority that the FM frequency of talk radio station KlubRádió expired and is up for bid. During the past year, the authority had extended the station&#39;s license for three months at a time. KlubRádió, which draws 300,000 listeners a day from among opposition supporters, raised over 500,000 euro from its listeners to offset the loss of advertizing income it suffered as a consequence. Today&#39;s bid, however, calls for an applicant that will broadcast music and local news, which would seem to exclude KlubRádió. The station argues for political reasons.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>authority;argues</elotte>
		<szavak>announces;it is targeted</szavak>
		<linkek>http://esbalogh.typepad.com/hungarianspectrum/2011/06/freedom-of-the-media-is-in-peril-in-hungary.html;http://www.economist.com/blogs/easternapproaches/2011/06/hungarian-media</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>June</honap>
		<nap>26</nap>
		<cim>Hungarian intellectuals write open letter to Hillary Clinton</cim>
		<szoveg>A group of Hungarian intellectuals and former dissidents, including György Konrád and Miklós Haraszti, write to Hillary Clinton, who is to visit Hungary shortly. Arguing that &quot;the rule of law has been seriously damaged in our country&quot; under the new government, they specifically criticize the &quot;omnipotent&quot; new media authority, &quot;composed solely of governing-party delegates, empowered to supervise not only broadcasting, but also the print and online media,&quot; which can impose &quot;massive fines.&quot; They say &quot;the public-service media were re-nationalized, and obliged to only use news provided by the state press agency.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>write</elotte>
		<szavak>an open letter</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.iprotest.hu/letter-to-hillary-clinton/</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>June</honap>
		<nap>30</nap>
		<cim>Hillary Clinton meets Orban, expresses concern over free press, judiciary</cim>
		<szoveg>After visiting Prime Minister Viktor Orban, U.S. Secretary of State Hillary Clinton praises Hungary&#39;s economic reform and Roma initiatives, but says she Hungary&#39;s constitutional court, media laws and new constitution with Orban. &quot;We ... talked very openly about preserving the democratic institutions of Hungary&quot; and the need to safeguard &quot;essential checks and balances,&quot; she said at a news conference with Orban. &quot;As friends of Hungary we expressed our concerns and particularly call for a real commitment to the independence of the judiciary, a free press and governmental transparency.&quot;</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>she</elotte>
		<szavak>also discussed</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.reuters.com/article/2011/06/30/hungary-clinton-idUSN1E75S2AP20110630</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>July</honap>
		<nap>1</nap>
		<cim>Media Commissioner investigation into reader comments on newspaper site sparks concern</cim>
		<szoveg>Media commissioner Jenő Bodonovich writes the left-wing newspaper Népszava to he is initiating an investigation into readers comments underneath an article, published on June 8, about President Schmitt and former President Mádl. The newspaper, which says it could not find out which remarks Bodonovich objected to specifically, recalls that the Media Council&#39;s spokeswoman previously said that reader comments do not fall under the media law. Media Council member Andras Koltay confirms in an interview on 3 July that the law does not apply to comments and fora, and only applies to content published after June 30. The announcement of the investigation, which Bodonovich initiated at the request of State Secretary Zoltan Kovacs, leads many news websites to close or curtail their comments sections.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>to</elotte>
		<szavak>announce</szavak>
		<linkek>http://hatc.hu/editor_article.php?aid=3404</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>July</honap>
		<nap>5</nap>
		<cim>One-third of public media workers to go</cim>
		<szoveg>The director of the new, centralised public media funding and management body, the MTVA, announces that 550 of the 3,300 public media workers in August. A total of 1,000 will be dismissed by year end. The new media laws stipulate that all public media news bulletins are to be produced by the national news agency MTI, for newsroom staff at the public broadcasters. Green politician Gergely Karácsony said that people were being fired for not being loyal enough to the government in a &quot;political purge&quot;. The MTVA argues that the old system was wasteful and opaque.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>workers;MTI,</elotte>
		<szavak>will be fired;reducing the need</szavak>
		<linkek>http://blogs.wsj.com/emergingeurope/2011/07/15/hungary-revamps-public-media/;http://www.budapesttimes.hu/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=19747&amp;Itemid=26</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
	<bejegyzes>
		<ev>2011</ev>
		<honap>July</honap>
		<nap>11</nap>
		<cim>Parliament adopts further amendments to media laws</cim>
		<szoveg>In its last session before the summer recess, Parliament adopts to the &quot;Media Act&quot; of 31 December 2010 and several other media and communications-related laws. One of them classifies unpaid fines imposed by the new media authority as public debt, meaning they can be collected by the tax authorities regardless of any legal challenge, and those who owe the fees are barred from frequency tenders. Another allows the NMHH, rather than an independent body, to define “public service”. A third amendment, however, seems responsive to criticisms of the new media laws. While the law had allowed unspecified &quot;authorities&quot; to oblige journalists to reveal their sources in “exceptionally justified cases” related to national security, public order and the prevention of crime, the amendment that only investigative authorities or a court can do so.</szoveg>
		<link>null</link>
		<foto>null</foto>
		<foto_alairas>null</foto_alairas>
		<video>null</video>
		<elotte>adopts;the amendment</elotte>
		<szavak>a number of amendments;specifies</szavak>
		<linkek>http://www.bbj.hu/politics/house-passes-multitude-of-amendments-to-media-law_58943;http://www.politics.hu/20110713/parliament-passes-amendments-to-media-law/</linkek>
	</bejegyzes>
</adat>